<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Twitter | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/twitter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-10T12:46:25+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Dick Move From Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/21/thoughts-dick-move-from-twitter/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T08:47:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/21/thoughts-dick-move-from-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Linden Tibbets on <a href="http://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a> alerts email:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>In recent weeks, Twitter announced policy changes* that will affect how applications and users like yourself can interact with Twitter&#8217;s data. As a result of these changes, on September 27th we will be removing all Twitter Triggers, disabling your ability to push tweets to places like email, Evernote and Facebook. All Personal and Shared Recipes using a Twitter Trigger will also be removed. Recipes using Twitter Actions and your ability to post new tweets via IFTTT will continue to work just fine.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>As a user, I thought I didn&#8217;t really mind the changes in Twitter&#8217;s policy. <!-- more -->
Well, I did feel disappointed when I couldn&#8217;t use Tweetbot for Mac anymore, but there was still the web and the crappy official app. So I just let it pass.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1P2b2R252y1j2c3t1Q3v/Screen%20Shot%202012-09-21%20at%208.50.20%20AM.png" alt="Tweetbot for Mac stopped working" /></p>

<p>Until today. For those who don&#8217;t know, <a href="http://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a> is an amazing service which can let the internet services you use to <em>talk</em> with each other. One of the <em>receipes</em> I used in IFTTT is to backup my tweets to my Dropbox. As you might know, it&#8217;s really difficult to see your old tweets. Thus the backing up. However, with the Twitter&#8217;s policy change, this won&#8217;t be possible anymore. Very disappointing. Because the tweets I tweeted are my own. I should have the rights to do whatever I want to do with it.</p>

<p>Anyhow, as the wise man says, it&#8217;s for FREE, if you don&#8217;t like it, don&#8217;t use it. As a matter of fact, I have reduced using Twitter directly. My tweets mostly came from Instagram or this blog using IFTTT.</p>

<p><br/>
/*====================================</p>

<p>Have you tried my new Mac app, <a href="http://kaomojiapp.com">Kaomoji for Mac</a>?</p>

<p>======================================*/</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
