<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mac | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/mac/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-29T12:40:40+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Change the Color of Finder Folder Icon in OSX Yosemite]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/10/19/how-to-change-the-color-of-finder-folder-icon-in-osx-yosemite/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-19T23:53:29+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/10/19/how-to-change-the-color-of-finder-folder-icon-in-osx-yosemite</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wasn&#8217;t really fond of the blue color of Finder folder icon in Yosemite. It&#8217;s too saturated. Luckily I wasn&#8217;t the only one. From <a href="http://yukiyamashina.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/how-to-change-the-color-of-default-folder-icons-in-OS-X-Yosemite/">Yuki Yamashina&#8217;s How to Change Color of Default Folder Icons in OSX Yosemite</a>, I could change the color of Finder folder icon.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Basically you just need to find the icons, edit, and restart.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>The icons are located in <code>/System/Library/CoreServices/CoreTypes.bundle/Contents/Resources/</code>. From Finder, just go to <code>System-&gt;Library-&gt;CoreServices</code> folder, then right click on <code>CoreTypes.bundle</code>, then click <code>Show Package Content</code>. Then open <code>Contents-&gt;Resources</code> folder.</p>

<p> <img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1z1W183F0m2F1k1T3y34/Screen%20Shot%202014-10-20%20at%2000.41.03.png" alt="location-of-osx-icons" /></p></li>
<li><p>There are several icons (.icns) you need to edit but the first one you should edit is <code>GenericFolderIcon.icns</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>Copy it first somewhere else then double click the file. Preview app will open and you can adjust the color from <code>Tools-&gt;Adjust Color...</code>. There are several images inside the icns file so you need to adjust the color of all the images. (If anybody knows how to batch edit the files let me know, please).</p>

<p> <img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/183c3d2H0K1N281a3s19/Screen%20Shot%202014-10-20%20at%2000.45.08.png" alt="change-icns-color-with-preview-osx" /></p></li>
<li><p>Once you&#8217;re done, save it, and copy it back to <code>/System/Library/CoreServices/CoreTypes.bundle/Contents/Resources/</code> folder. You will be prompted to enter Administrator password.</p></li>
<li><p>Now the important step. You need to clear the icon cache by executing the following commands in Terminal.</p>

<pre><code> sudo find /private/var/folders/ -name com.apple.dock.iconcache -exec rm {} \;
 sudo find /private/var/folders/ -name com.apple.iconservices -exec rm -rf {} \;
</code></pre></li>
<li><p>Restart your Mac.</p></li>
<li>Do the same thing for other icons such as <code>ApplicationsFolderIcon.icns</code>, <code>DesktopFolderIcon.icns</code>, etc.</li>
</ol>


<p>It&#8217;s a bit of work but at least the folder icon is pleasant to my eyes now.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1v0f33211J2q2P38161i/finder-folder-icons.png" alt="change-yosemite-finder-folder-icon-color" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[25 Must Have Apps for Your Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/09/28/25-must-have-apps-for-your-mac/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-28T15:50:16+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/09/28/25-must-have-apps-for-your-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="wide-image">
<img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1Q1c2q1L2n2s3J1e0e2L/Optimized-macs.jpg" alt="My Apple products family">
</p>


<p>These are the 25+ apps that I found really useful on my Mac. There are apps that aid software development (iOS mostly) and there are also apps for general activities.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><em>Note: The links are affiliate links. If you&#8217;re not into it, you can just simply google these apps. But I really appreciate if you use these links</em> （＾ω＾）</p>

<p><em>PS: If you know better affiliate program, <a href="https://twitter.com/nicnocquee">let me know please</a>!</em></p>

<h2>General</h2>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/1">DragonDrop</a>. Drag and drop done right on the Mac. The price is nothing compared to useful this small little app is. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/dragondrop/id499148234?l=en&amp;mt=12">$4.99 USD on the Mac App Store</a></li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/2">Instashare</a>. Transfering files between Mac and iPhone has been a pain in the ass. Yosemite <em>might</em> solve this problem with the Airdrop feature, but in the mean time, Instashare works wonderfully. And it works on older devices as well! <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/instashare-transfer-files/id685953216?l=en&amp;mt=12">$3.99 USD on the Mac App Store</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/3">Disk Inventory X</a>. FREE. Disk Inventory X shows which folders that are eating up the space in your Mac. Thanks to it I managed to clear up more than 30GB of free space from my Mac.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/4">1Password</a>. Apple has iCloud Keychain to help with passwords management. But I find it unreliable most of the time. For example, there are times when the Safari on iOS doesn&#8217;t show auto-fill for username and password on a website. 1Password just works. And it can secure more than just login information, it can also secure credit card information, Wifi router password, notes, and many more. It can even sync your passwords to Dropbox or iCloud. It&#8217;s worth the price. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/1password-password-manager/id443987910?l=en&amp;mt=12">$49.99 on the Mac App Store</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kaomojiapp.com">Kaomoji for Mac</a>. <em>Disclaimer: This is my app</em>. With Kaomoji for Mac, you don&#8217;t need to copy and paste kaomoji anymore. Keyboard shortcut and tons of kaomojis in many different categories. $3.00 to unlock all kaomojis.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/5">CloudApp</a>. FREE. With CloudApp, I can quickly share screenshots.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/6">MPlayerX</a>. FREE and Open Source. VLC has been the most popular video player but I really like MPlayerX simplicity. And autoplay the next episode is very neat.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/7">LaunchBar</a>. €24.00. I&#8217;m using it mainly to quickly launch apps and its clipboard history.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/8">Skitch</a>. FREE. The simplest app to annotate images. If you don&#8217;t want Skitch to save to Evernote like I do, simply go to <em>Preferences -> Sync -> Save New Skitch Notes to Evernote: Manual</em></li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/9">Mou</a>. FREE. A very simple Markdown editor. All of the posts in this blog were written in Mou.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/A">GifRocket</a>. FREE (for now). A simple app to create GIF from video.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.downthemall.net">DownThemAll</a>. FREE. DownThemAll is a powerful Firefox extension to download stuff. It can increase download speed significantly. Seriously. Download all files with certain filetypes feature had helped me to download all PDFs quickly from <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/wwdc/2014/">Apple&#8217;s WWDC website</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/B">Reflector</a>. $12.99. Easily and wirelessly display my iPhone to my Mac. Even video playing on the iPhone can be displayed on the Mac. Unfortunately it doesn&#8217;t work if the video is longer than 10 minutes. Bug probably.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/O">Knock</a>. FREE. My Mac doesn&#8217;t really need Knock. But it&#8217;s just fun to unlock the Mac by knocking.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/D">OpenEmu</a>. FREE and Open Source. I&#8217;m not a gamer but sometimes it&#8217;s fun to play retro games and OpenEmu is awesome for it.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/N">Day One</a>. Day One helps me to keep track what I have been doing. Syncs with the iOS app via Dropbox or iCloud. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/day-one/id422304217?mt=12">$9.99 on the Mac App Store</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/E">AppCleaner</a>. FREE. Most of the times apps create files throughout the system. Simply removing the app doesn&#8217;t necesserily removes the temporary files. AppCleaner finds the small files and deletes them.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/C">HandBrake</a>. FREE and Open Source. Convert video from nearly every format.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Development Tools</h2>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/F">Go2Shell</a>. Opens Terminal to the current directory in Finder. Wonder why Apple doesn&#8217;t have this feature by default. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/go2shell/id445770608?l=en&amp;mt=12">FREE on the Mac App Store</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/G">SourceTree</a>. A nice GUI client for Git. FREE.</li>
<li><a href="http://revealapp.com">Reveal</a>. Reveal app has saved me a lot of time debugging user interface bugs in my app. $89 USD.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/H">PaintCode</a>. I&#8217;ve been using PaintCode 1 to turn drawings into code. But I just found out that there is PaintCode 2 with more awesome features. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/paintcode-2/id808809998?l=en&amp;mt=12">$99.99 on the Mac App Store</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/I">CodeRunner</a>. Sometimes you just want to quickly test if a snippet of code works as you expected. CodeRunner helps you to do that. It&#8217;s like Swift playground but with support for many different languages. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/coderunner/id433335799?mt=12">$9.99 on the Mac App Store</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.pixelmator.com">Pixelmator</a>. Pixelmator is a brilliant Photoshop replacement. I use it to quickly edit assets for my apps. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/pixelmator/id407963104?l=en&amp;mt=12">$29.99 on the Mac App Store</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/J">Simpholders</a>. A small app to quickly access the folder of applications you have in iOS simulator. FREE.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/K">Postman REST Client</a>. Easily test API by creating requests and view the responses in a beautiful way. FREE.</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/L">Mockupphone</a>. It&#8217;s not a Mac app but if you want to easily wrap your app screenshots in device mockup, then you should bookmark Mockupphone. FREE (Pay with your e-mail address).</li>
<li><a href="http://l.nicnocquee.com/M">Makeappicon</a>. Another website you should bookmark if you&#8217;re an app developer. Simply upload a big size of your icon image, then download the app icons in many different sizes. FREE (Pay with e-mail address).</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Enter Unicode Characters in Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/10/16/how-to-enter-unicode-characters-in-mac/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-16T18:54:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/10/16/how-to-enter-unicode-characters-in-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I found out about <a href="http://icomoon.io/">icomoon</a> and was wondering how to use the icon fonts on Mac. Turns out it&#8217;s not so difficult.</p>

<p>Skipt this steps if you already have icon fonts.</p>

<ol>
<li>Go to <a href="http://icomoon.io/app/">icomoon app</a>, select some fonts. (Tip: You can drag and select multiple fonts quickly.)</li>
<li>Generate the font then download.</li>
<li>Install the downloaded icomoon.ttf font by double clicking it.</li>
</ol>


<!-- more -->


<p>Now the fun part.</p>

<ol>
<li>Open System Preferences.</li>
<li>Select Language &amp; Text.</li>
<li>Check Unicode Hex Input in Input Source.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3I3s2v121n3d1i2r311Z/Screen%20Shot%202013-10-16%20at%207.08.13%20PM.png" alt="Unicode Hex Input in System Preferences OS X" /></p>

<p>That&#8217;s it! Well not quite. The secret to use the font is <strong>by choosing Unicode Hex Input from Input menu in menu bar, then type the unicode code while pressing Option (⌥) key</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0a1x2q2I3K3L1J05472Z/Screen%20Shot%202013-10-16%20at%206.45.42%20PM.png" alt="Change Input from Menu bar" /></p>

<p>So for example, to insert ♥, while pressing Option, type 2665. (Option+2665). The same goes for icon fonts generated by icomoon. Insert the unicde character then change the font to icomoon font.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0D2c3Z1W2d0M163D3g3k/Screen%20Shot%202013-10-16%20at%206.50.25%20PM.png" alt="Insert unicode and use custom icon font in Pixelmator" /></p>

<p>Now have fun with custom icon fonts!</p>

<p>Reference: <a href="http://cl.ly/image/0c031i190x18">TUAW</a>.
You can find me on <a href="http://twitter.com/nicnocquee">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[REVIEW] Mac Photo Bundle]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/23/review-mac-photo-bundle/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T12:55:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/23/review-mac-photo-bundle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.mightydeals.com?refID=81ccb6">Mighty Deals</a> have an interesting deal for non-pro photography enthusiasts like me, <a href="http://www.mightydeals.com/deal/macphun-photo-bundle.html?refID=81ccb6">The Mac Photo Bundle</a>. There are three apps: Snapheal, FX Studio Pro, and ColorStrokes. My favorite and the one that make the deal worth it is F<a href="http://www.fxphotostudioapp.com/">X Studio Pro</a>.<!-- more --></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2I3L1i2S2B2Q1i352U1X/Screen%20Shot%202012-09-23%20at%2012.17.10%20PM.png" alt="FX Studio Pro for Mac" /></p>

<p>It&#8217;s basically <a href="http://campl.us/">Camera+</a> for Mac. Lots of filters and frames to choose from. Easy navigation. Switching to another filter is easy, fast, and smooth, at least in my 11-inch, Mid 2012 Macbook Air.</p>

<p>Second one for my favorite is <a href="http://www.colorsplashphoto.com/">ColorStrokes</a>. From the website:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>With ColorStrokes you have the entire color palette in your hands. You can recolor the image and even bring colors to the black and white shots, thus letting your photo creativity truly blossom.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/191h203H252P1r1z0k2J/Screen%20Shot%202012-09-23%20at%201.16.39%20PM.png" alt="ColorStrokes for Mac in action" /></p>

<p>And the last is <a href="http://www.snapheal.com/">Snapheal</a>. To be honest, I&#8217;m not satisfied with this one. It didn&#8217;t work as expected and advertised. It depends on the photo and the object you will try to remove. Works better on small objects. Though the developers included interesting UX to prevent you from getting bored while waiting for the processing to finish.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2i3M152M3E0M1A3j3747/Screen%20Shot%202012-09-23%20at%2012.28.15%20PM.png" alt="Snapheal in action" /></p>

<p>FX Studio Pro is $39.99 (3,450JPY) in the <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/fx-photo-studio-pro/id432888949?mt=12">Mac App Store</a>. ColorStrokes is $4 in the <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/color-splash-studio/id459413843?mt=12">Mac App Store</a>, though it&#8217;s 30% OFF for a limited time now. Snapheal is $19.99 in the <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/snapheal/id480623975?mt=12">Mac App Store</a>. All three in this <a href="http://www.mightydeals.com/deal/macphun-photo-bundle.html?refID=81ccb6">bundle</a> will set you back $20 (1,600JPY) only. Grab it while it lasts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[NEWS] Kaomoji for Mac 1.5 Is Out!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/19/news-kaomoji-for-mac-1-dot-5-is-out/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T10:41:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/19/news-kaomoji-for-mac-1-dot-5-is-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/1e74e32c01fa11e2ab4c22000a1d0350_7.jpg" alt="Updated #Kaomoji for #Mac! Now with Japanese localization. 日本語でMac向け顔文字を使いましょう！（＾＿＾）☆ http://kaomojiapp.com #japan #apple #顔文字" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
If you haven&#8217;t, you can download Kaomoji for Mac <a href="http://kaomojiapp.com">here</a>. And if you like it, let me know in <a href="http://www.facebook.com/kaomoji.mac">Kaomoji for Mac Facebook page</a>
<br/>（＾＿－）≡★</p>

<p>/*===============================</p>

<p>How about say hi to <a href="http://twitter.com/nicnocquee">me</a> if you like this post?</p>

<p>================================*/</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
