<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iphone | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/iphone/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-08T09:20:15+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] January 4 was my real new year]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/05/thoughts-january-4-was-my-real-new-year/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T01:06:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/05/thoughts-january-4-was-my-real-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I write this sentence on my MBA which rests on my lap, the digital clock at the top right corner shows "Fri Jan 4 11:26:50 PM". In around 30 minutes, it will be January 5. It's been 4 days since the year 2013 closed the door of 2012 and came to our life. The holiday for most people in Japan has ended yesterday. Yet here I am feeling like finally I can say "Happy new year!" sincerelly.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Danny Choo asked good questions on his post <a href="http://www.dannychoo.com/post/en/26806/2013+New+Years+Greetings.html">2013 New Years Greetings!</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Happy new year folks! Hows your new year celebrations?<br/>But before you answer that, have you ever thought to yourself why we celebrate the new year? Is it because we want to celebrate what we have achieved in the previous year? Is it because we are celebrating what we want to do in the up n coming year? Is it because we are celebrating the fact that most of us get time off work/school?</p></blockquote></p>

<p>In my opinion, new year is a good time to start things new. Either starting something really new, or simply restarting what we have been doing. But remember what <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix_Revolutions">Oracle</a> said,</p>

<p><blockquote><p>everything that has a beginning has an end</p></blockquote></p>

<p>There are ways to read that between the line, but I'd like to think that to really begin, we need to end something. I had not finished what I wanted to finish in 2012. Thus, I did not fully celebrate new year.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0G3e350L3m1a2K1N0U1M/Screen%20Shot%202013-01-04%20at%2011.42.19%20PM.png" alt="Last day of 2011 with friends in Ise" /></p>

<p>This year, we, as in me and wifey, <em>celebrated</em> new year differently compared to previous years. Last year, we spent new year in Ise together with our friends. However, this year it was just the two of us in our apartment. We were just there sitting on the yellow sofa I got nearly three years ago, if my memory serves me right, from an Indian guy whom I didn't (still don't) know. We were watching Japanese TV Show called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K%C5%8Dhaku_Uta_Gassen">Kohaku (紅白) Uta Gassen</a> where a bunch of Japanese singers and musicians was divided into two teams, red and white teams, and they competed with each other.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/222Q0y0W1Y2h3I3s460T/maki-chan1.png" alt="Maki-chan on Kohaku" /></p>

<p>But we weren't really watching the show. We were most of the time looking at our Macbook's monitors. I was busy with XCode while wifey was busy with Photoshop. We were working on Scribeit. Scribeit is the second app I put in Apple Store. It is my first paid app. And it is the only paid app at this moment. It's been two years since I updated it. It was never even updated to support retina display when iPhone 4 was released. Despite of that, number of downloads every month never reaches zero. So I finally made up my mind to update this baby and to finish it before 2012 came to an end. And my wife helped me with the graphics and stuff.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2B081D0J0h1c0c450312/9gag2013.png" alt="2013 is the first year since 1987 to have four different numbers" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, everything doesn't always work as planned. As this part of the world turned from December 31 to January 1, Scribeit was not completely done yet. An unexpected behaviour in the app prevented me from fully enjoying the moment where people celebrated the first year since 1987 to have four different numbers!</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3h0o2n1X3a3T0j0R1y0s/Screen%20Shot%202013-01-05%20at%2012.17.08%20AM.png" alt="New Scribeit 2013" /></p>

<p>At around 3AM of January 1, I finally found the problem. I closed my Mac and decided to wrap things up in the morning. Then came January 2. Followed by January 3. You see, I realized that contrary to popular belief, <em>finishing</em> is way more difficult than starting. You can always start <em>small</em>, but you cannot finish small. You can start from small things one by one. But you cannot finish only a part of the whole. Of course there's no such thing as completely <strong>finish</strong>. There's always something to add. Or to reduce. I'm talking about finishing the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product">MVP</a>. You cannot ship a half ass product. You need to reach that state of MVP. And here's a fact: even an MVP has many check lists to complete. If you think starting is hard, finishing will be hell for you.</p>

<p>So, on the last day of new year holiday, I was finally able to submit our baby to App Store. We think it looks amazing. We love it. And we think you'll love it too. ♡＾▽＾♡ Follow me on <a href="https://twitter.com/nicnocquee">Twitter</a> to know when the update is available on the App Store.</p>

<p>☆☆ Happy new year!</p>

<p>☆☆ 明けましておめでとうございます！</p>

<p>☆☆ Selamat tahun baru!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[NEWS] Monoco for iPhone Update is available now]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/news-monoco-for-iphone-update-is-available-now/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T10:55:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/news-monoco-for-iphone-update-is-available-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2U2H0J0g1F2V422R0V3O/update.png" alt="Monoco updated" /></p>

<p>An update to support iPhone 5's taller screen and some bug fixes. Head to the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/monoco/id539376693?ls=1&amp;mt=8">Apple Store</a>, please.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2Y3M2G1T1B0n1b0G1f1x/credits.png" alt="Silver member achieved!" /></p>

<p>And a lovely surprise: Achieved Silver membership in <a href="https://monoco.jp/signup?ref=n">Monoco.jp</a>! Which means I got 3,000円 credits! ヽ(｀◇´)/</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[NEWS] Monoco iPhone App is now available on the Japan App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/15/news-monoco-iphone-app-is-now-available-on-the-japan-app-store/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T18:08:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/15/news-monoco-iphone-app-is-now-available-on-the-japan-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://static.flutterscape.net/nl/ibwot.png" alt="Monoco iPhone アプリ" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/25100Z21171l3Q023s2K/%E5%86%99%E7%9C%9F%202012-10-15%2013%2037%2044.png" alt="Monoco on the App Store" /></p>

<p>M to the O to the N to the O to the C to the O. For those who love beautiful discounted products. Japan only. Grab <a href="https://monoco.jp/signup?ref=n">Monoco</a> for iPhone <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/jp/app/monoco/id539376693?ls=1&amp;mt=8">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[REVIEW] Transfer photos from memory card to and from iPhone using AirStash]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/04/review-transfer-photos-from-memory-card-to-and-from-iphone-using-airstash/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T09:47:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/04/review-transfer-photos-from-memory-card-to-and-from-iphone-using-airstash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>iPhone, with all the great things, has many shortcomings. One of the those that still does not make sense to me is its inability to transfer photos from memory card using the Camera Connection Kit while its big brother iPad can do it. Surely iPhone 4/4S/5 has the horsepower to read and transfer photos. There's no reason for this restriction. Unfortunately, there's no sign that Apple will change this policy in the near future.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Here is where <a href="http://www.airstash.com/">Airstash</a> comes and saves the day. Airstash is a wifi card reader. Insert your memory card (SD/SDHC) to it, turn it on, connect to its wifi network from your iPhone, and you can now copy your photos to iPhone's camera roll. Easy and simple. Recommended.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0n0O0v1p1n12323Q071v/resized-0.JPG" alt="Airstash to transfer photos from memory card to/from iPhone." /></p>

<br />


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2t161k1d3k2F3C043z0p/resized-2.JPG" alt="Airstash can be used to transfer other files, not only photos." /></p>

<br />


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/432b0M3d1o3O0L0t3r2J/resized-1.JPG" alt="Airstash can also stream movies to iPhone, though I haven't tried this one yet." /></p>

<br />


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2W0n193E270S2Q1O0F3D/resized-04.JPG" alt="Airstash is very light" /></p>

<br />


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/302R1e0R1Q2U1B0P0o23/iphone.jpg" alt="Airstash iPhone app. Can use GoodReader or any app that can access WebDav Server actually." /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] iOS 6 Maps: It just works. NOT!]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/20/share-ios-6-maps-it-just-works-not/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T17:16:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/20/share-ios-6-maps-it-just-works-not</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SBS on <a href="http://www.japanmobiletech.com/2012/09/ios-6-maps-fail-in-japan.html">iOS 6 maps FAIL in Japan</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Looking for Osaka Station? Well, it's apparently not in the database. That'll piss off Hashimoto!</p></blockquote></p>

<p><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-JLuGOmWk5t4/UFrJuaCJ-TI/AAAAAAAABEY/Uuj87fkCMCU/s320/osaka.jpg" alt="Osaka station" /></p>

<p>Blasphemy! Instead of that stupid ads, Samsung should attack Apple with this disgrace.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
