<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Learn | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/learn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-09T02:42:55+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[JAPANESE] Today's Nihonggo #2]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/04/japanese-todays-nihonggo-number-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T09:36:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/04/japanese-todays-nihonggo-number-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another week, another Japanese class. As usual, learned many new stuffs (for me) this week.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>〜ようと思います。「I think I will 〜」</p>

<p>Examples:</p>

<ol>
<li>汗をかいたので、後でシャワーを浴びようと思う。「Since I&#8217;m sweating, I think I&#8217;ll take shower.」</li>
<li>会社をやめて、１年ぐらい留学しようと思っています。「I&#8217;m thinking of quitting my job, then study abroad.」</li>
<li>この仕事は大切だから、アルバイトの人に頼もうと思いません。「This job is very important, so I won&#8217;t ask part-timer to do it.」
<!-- more --></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>〜ようとしている。「about to」</p>

<p>Examples:</p>

<ol>
<li>赤信号なのに渡ろうとしている児童を注意した。「Even though the traffic light went red, I was cautious of kid about to cross the street.」</li>
<li>大きな夕日が海に沈もうとしていた。「The big sunset was about to sink to the sea」</li>
<li>授業が始まろうとしているとき、私の携帯電話に母から「お父さんが倒れた」という電話がかかってきた。「When the class was about to start, I got a phone call from my mom telling me that dad collapsed.」</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>〜っこない。「There&#8217;s no chance, no way」</p>

<p>Examples:</p>

<ol>
<li>こんな難しい本を買ってやったって、小学校１年生の太郎には分かりっこない。「There&#8217;s no way Taro the first year junior high school kid could buy and read this difficult book.」</li>
<li>そんな高い家賃、僕たちに支払えっこない。「There&#8217;s no way we can afford such expensive rent.」</li>
<li>小さな子供がこんなに遠くまで一人で来られっこない。「There&#8217;s no way a little kid can go this far alone.」</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>〜がたい。「Difficult to」</p>

<p>Examples:</p>

<ol>
<li>あの元気なひろしが病気になるたんて信じがたいことです。「It&#8217;s difficult to believe that that healthy Hiroshi became sick.」</li>
<li>最近、家族間の殺人など、信じがたいニュースが多い。「Lately, there are many hard to believe news about murder in family.」</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>〜ないことには、「Unless」</p>

<p>Examples:</p>

<ol>
<li>確認してみないことには、申し上げられません。「I can&#8217;t say unless I confirm it first」</li>
<li>ある商品が売れるかどうかは、市場調査をしてみないことには、わからない。「Unless I do market research, I cannot tell whether a product can be sold.」</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>


<p>And many more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[JAPANESE] Today's Nihonggo #1]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/26/japanese-todays-nihonggo-number-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:11:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/26/japanese-todays-nihonggo-number-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://distilleryimage10.s3.amazonaws.com/fb379d44072311e29c1122000a1e8a73_7.jpg" alt="Reviewing Japanese ... #japan #kobe #osaka #kansai #manga #anime #japanese #learn" /></p>

<p>Few things I learned from todays&#8217;s nihonggo class:</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>〜ずに。which means 「<em>without</em>」.
Example: 「暑いので、子供はふとんをかけずに寝ています。」「The kid is sleeping without <em>futon</em> cause it&#8217;s hot.」 The sentence I learned today was 「出張で植木に水をやることができず、枯らしてしまった。」 which I think the meaning is 「Because of work trip, I cannot water the plant in the garden, now they withered.」</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>〜きれない。which is the negative of 〜きれる which means 「<em>all</em>」. Example: 「あの商品は人気があるらしく、発売と同時に売りきれてしまった。」「That product seems so popular that it got sold out completely when the sales started.」 The sentence I learned today was 「彼女の家には数えきれないほどの人形があるそうだ。」which means 「She has uncountable number of dolls in her house」.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>〜につれ　which means 「<em>as in proportion to</em>」. Example: 「日本語が上手になるにつれて、友達が増え、日本での生活が楽しくなってきた。」「As I get better in Japanese, I get more friends, and life in Japan is getting fun.」The sentence I learned today was 「秋が深まるにつれ、セーターが売れるようになる。」which means 「As autumn gets closer, sweaters are being sold.」</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>〜かねる　which is the polite version of 〜できない。
Example: 「ここでは分かりかねますので、あちらのカウンターでお聞きください。」「We don&#8217;t understand here, so please ask the counter over there.」 The sentence I learned today was 「哲学者の話が分かりかねることはよくある話だ。」which means 「I don&#8217;t really understand the talk of a philosopher」.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>〜にかける　which means 「<em>when it comes to</em>」. Example: 「足の速さにかけては自信があったのですが、若い人にはもう勝てません。」「I have confidence when it comes to my feet&#8217;s speed, but I can no longer win against young people.」 The sentence I learned today was 「歌のうまさにかけては会社の中で彼の右にでる者がない。」 which means 「When it comes to singing, nobody in the company is on a par with him.」</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>And many new kanji. Japanese is difficult orz</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
