<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apple | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-04T17:32:21+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] iPad Mini after 3 days]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/05/thoughts-ipad-mini-after-3-days/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T22:57:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/05/thoughts-ipad-mini-after-3-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2012/11/05Apple-Sells-Three-Million-iPads-in-Three-Days.html">Apple managed to sell three million iPads in three days</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>CUPERTINO, California—November 5, 2012—Apple® today announced it has sold three million iPads in just three days since the launch of its new iPad® mini and fourth generation iPad—double the previous first weekend milestone of 1.5 million Wi-Fi only models sold for the third generation iPad in March.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I can't believe it's been three days since I started using iPad Mini. It feels like I've been using it for a long time. It just fits to my life (and my jacket pocket and my bag) better than the big bro iPad. Even without the retina display, I enjoy reading books and articles on it. Apparently I am not the only one.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Interesting bits on the announcement is that Apple didn't announce how many iPad Mini they have sold. It's 3 millions iPads which include both iPad Mini and the iPad 4 (or the Newer iPad, whatever). So I thought it could also mean that the majority of the iPads sold is the iPad 4 and nobody wanted iPad mini. But Mr. Tim Cook answered in the next paragraph,</p>

<p><blockquote><p>“Customers around the world love the new iPad mini and fourth generation iPad,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “We set a new launch weekend record and practically sold out of iPad minis. We're working hard to build more quickly to meet the incredible demand.”</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Sold out. So the <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/felix-salmon/2012/10/24/why-apple-doesnt-care-about-its-competition/">pricing indeed was not intended to compete with the competitors' tablet</a>, but to fill up the gap between Apple's line of products.</p>

<p>But why didn't Apple announce the real number of iPad mini sold? Now that I think about it, the answer to this question proves that what I thought about Apple was wrong. I didn't write or post or tweet about that thought (because you know, you don't really have to tell your so-called friends and followers about everything), but I was hoping Apple was not going to make iPad mini. I thought by releasing a small version of the iPad <em>after</em> Google released the most praised Android tablet, Google Nexus 7, Apple has fallen back and became a <em>follower</em>. But it seems not the case here. iPad mini is to iPad what Macbook Air is to Macbook Pro. Or it can also be, iPad mini is to iPad what Macbook Air 11" is to Macbook Air 13". As far as I know, Apple never announced individual numbers of MBA and MBP sold. Or each numbers of MBA 11" and MBA 13". They are all Macbooks. They are the choices Apple gives to the customers. Same with the iPads.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0C2w2H44473i1b313m2A/IMG_7552%20copy.jpg" alt="iPad mini" /></p>

<p>I have a feeling that when Apple finally releases iPad mini with retina display, the history of iPhone cannibalizing the iPod will repeat once again. We'll see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Yet another iPad Mini first impression]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/02/thoughts-ipad-mini-first-impression/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T16:48:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/02/thoughts-ipad-mini-first-impression</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8053/8147103832_3e00427baf.jpg" alt="iPad Miniゲット" /></p>

<p>Long story short, I love iPad Mini. And I'm gonna love even more the next version of iPad Mini with Retina Display.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8192/8147068767_7a86db0a60.jpg" alt="Back of Mini" /></p>

<p>So I was about to write a post to respond to a friend's status update regarding Apple, but I remembered I have decided not to respond to any tweets, comments, updates, posts ridiculing Apple. It's a waste of time, energy, and soul. Furthermore, it's the poster's rights to say what he/she wants about anything. Although in this particular instance, he specifically asked Apple fans to read and understand. Which brought me to question the purpose of the status update. Because when I bad-mouthed Google, Amazon, Samsung, etc, I never ask the users of each company to read and understand. I have no agenda to convince the users to ditch the service/product. Since it is their right to choose and use whatever they want to use. I just spoke my mind. And who could say that the service or product that I endorse will be better for him/her. Or who could say that the service or product that I try to sell will stay good as it is now. I couldn't figure out his point.</p>

<p><img src="http://distilleryimage10.s3.amazonaws.com/02741656248d11e2a33422000a1ea02a_7.jpg" alt="The only line for iPad mini! So short!! #apple #shinsaibashi #osaka #kansai #japan" /></p>

<p>Anyway, today, in Japan, iPad Mini is available in the Apple Store. So I went to the only Apple Store in Osaka, Apple Store Shinsaibashi. As expected, there were no ridiculously long line for the iPad Mini. I just went to the store, tried the iPad Mini a little bit, went to the staff, paid, unboxed, and done. Very fast.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8188/8147068869_fd03a2c699.jpg" alt="Fits in my hand!" /></p>

<p>First impression, like many others who had the priviledge of playing with it in the US early, this thing is so freaking <strong>LIGHT</strong>! It fits perfectly on my hand. Very easy to use with one hand. Even without the retina display, it feels comfortable for reading.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8468/8147104266_a35cdc212a.jpg" alt="Easy to hold" /></p>

<p>Typing on iPad Mini was also giving a good impression. If you have used the big bro iPad, you'll notice that it's not so easy to type on it while standing. But typing on iPad Mini is a joy.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8335/8147069177_5751c1d112.jpg" alt="Retina display please" /></p>

<p>iPad Mini + Macbook Air 11" is the best combo for me for now. Once both get enhanced with Retina Display, it will be perfect.</p>

<p>So which color did you get?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] The best explanation of Apple's Reshuffle]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/30/share-the-best-explanation-of-apples-reshuffle/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-30T15:44:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/30/share-the-best-explanation-of-apples-reshuffle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>John Moltz on <a href="http://verynicewebsite.net/2012/10/forstall-browett-leaving-apple/">Forstall and Browett Leaving Apple</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Tim Cook’s statement here is clear: Apple will not tolerate executives whose names end in double consonants. That’s just smart policy.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>LOL.</p>

<!-- more -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] I hope Apple will never do this]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-i-hope-apple-will-never-do-this/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T23:39:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-i-hope-apple-will-never-do-this</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By "this" I mean what <a href="http://www.amazon.com/">Amazon</a> just did:</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2b351X3f1J0y2K1q0x23/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-29%20at%2010.48.51%20PM.png" alt="Amazon attack iPad mini" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>or what Samsung did:</p>

<p><img src="http://kensegall.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/120916_samsung_ad.jpg" alt="Samsung gave a blow at Apple" /></p>

<p>If you still cannot grasp what I mean, it's the crappy way of advertising the product by comparing with the competitor. At least do it in a funny and classy way like Mac vs PC.</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/K0Mt6dqFv4k" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Oh, and if you're interested in the revised versions of the two ads above via <a href="http://m.imore.com/copy-editing-amazons-kindle-fire-vs-ipad-mini-ad">iMore</a></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1U0B083v42051S1N2P2A/amazon_kindle_fire_vs_ipad_mini_v2-2.jpg" alt="Kindle Fire HD vs iPad Mini revised comparison" /></p>

<p>and <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17852_3-57513782-71/apple-fanboys-fight-back-against-samsung/">CNet</a>:</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/25060I3T1V2I440n3Z1C/Real_Samsung_Ad_610x1179.png" alt="Galaxy S3 vs iPhone from Apple fan's point of view" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Lover? Hater? It's all about Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-lover-hater-its-all-about-apple/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T22:31:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-lover-hater-its-all-about-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Check out these two videos, Shit Android Users Say and Shit Apple Fanatics Say:</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7huae767Rxg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>




<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FFhjDX-DUew" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>




<!-- more -->


<p>It's hard not to notice from the two videos that Android users tend to show their <em>hatred/dislike</em> towards Apple, while on the other hand, Apple users tend to show their <em>love</em> towards Apple itself. Which is kind of weird since we all know that there was one person in Apple who hated Android so much.</p>

<p>I always see those who hate Apple as broken hearted people. It could be an unrequited love. Or it could be a relationship that went wrong at some point. Either way, they cannot help but bitching about Apple as a result of disappointment.</p>

<p>Android world needs more people who are proud of having an Android device than those who keep complaining about device that they are not going to use anyway.</p>

<p>Anyhow, We just looooooooooooooove Apple. ♡＾▽＾♡ Except the Apple Map. (¬д¬。)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
