<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apple | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-30T15:48:37+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] The best explanation of Apple's Reshuffle]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/30/share-the-best-explanation-of-apples-reshuffle/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-30T15:44:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/30/share-the-best-explanation-of-apples-reshuffle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>John Moltz on <a href="http://verynicewebsite.net/2012/10/forstall-browett-leaving-apple/">Forstall and Browett Leaving Apple</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Tim Cook’s statement here is clear: Apple will not tolerate executives whose names end in double consonants. That’s just smart policy.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>LOL.</p>

<!-- more -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] I hope Apple will never do this]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-i-hope-apple-will-never-do-this/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T23:39:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-i-hope-apple-will-never-do-this</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By "this" I mean what <a href="http://www.amazon.com/">Amazon</a> just did:</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2b351X3f1J0y2K1q0x23/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-29%20at%2010.48.51%20PM.png" alt="Amazon attack iPad mini" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>or what Samsung did:</p>

<p><img src="http://kensegall.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/120916_samsung_ad.jpg" alt="Samsung gave a blow at Apple" /></p>

<p>If you still cannot grasp what I mean, it's the crappy way of advertising the product by comparing with the competitor. At least do it in a funny and classy way like Mac vs PC.</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/K0Mt6dqFv4k" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Oh, and if you're interested in the revised versions of the two ads above via <a href="http://m.imore.com/copy-editing-amazons-kindle-fire-vs-ipad-mini-ad">iMore</a></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1U0B083v42051S1N2P2A/amazon_kindle_fire_vs_ipad_mini_v2-2.jpg" alt="Kindle Fire HD vs iPad Mini revised comparison" /></p>

<p>and <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17852_3-57513782-71/apple-fanboys-fight-back-against-samsung/">CNet</a>:</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/25060I3T1V2I440n3Z1C/Real_Samsung_Ad_610x1179.png" alt="Galaxy S3 vs iPhone from Apple fan's point of view" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Lover? Hater? It's all about Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-lover-hater-its-all-about-apple/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T22:31:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-lover-hater-its-all-about-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Check out these two videos, Shit Android Users Say and Shit Apple Fanatics Say:</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7huae767Rxg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>




<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FFhjDX-DUew" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>




<!-- more -->


<p>It's hard not to notice from the two videos that Android users tend to show their <em>hatred/dislike</em> towards Apple, while on the other hand, Apple users tend to show their <em>love</em> towards Apple itself. Which is kind of weird since we all know that there was one person in Apple who hated Android so much.</p>

<p>I always see those who hate Apple as broken hearted people. It could be an unrequited love. Or it could be a relationship that went wrong at some point. Either way, they cannot help but bitching about Apple as a result of disappointment.</p>

<p>Android world needs more people who are proud of having an Android device than those who keep complaining about device that they are not going to use anyway.</p>

<p>Anyhow, We just looooooooooooooove Apple. ♡＾▽＾♡ Except the Apple Map. (¬д¬。)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] iMac was the queen of the apple event]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/thoughts-imac-was-the-queen-of-the-apple-event/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T08:11:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/thoughts-imac-was-the-queen-of-the-apple-event</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1v1O2A290s0k0p0r2A1t/ipadmini.jpg" alt="The iPad mini" /></p>

<p>First thing I did this morning when I woke up was to pick up my iPad which was lying on the side of my bed all night, opened Safari, typed in apple.com. iPad mini was the first thing I saw. Watching the video of the iPad mini, me and wifey thought, "we want it!" It looks lighter, and easier to hold.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>But then, John Gruber <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2012/10/23/ipad-mini-dalrymple">said</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Screen resolution-wise, it’s exactly what I expected for a 163 PPI display in 2012: noticeably nicer than the 133 PPI iPad 1/2, noticeably worse than the 266 PPI iPad 3/4. The iPad Mini display seems brighter and to have better contrast than the iPhone 3GS display, but unsurprisingly, rendered text looks exactly like it does on the 3GS.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><strong>Rendered text looks exactly like it does on the 3GS</strong>. Now that's a turn off. The thing I like the most from iPhone 4/4S and the (not so) new iPad was the retina display which display text sharply. If this iPad mini cannot do that, I guess we'll wait for the next generation.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0W142R2S1J3B080O1A0b/imac.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Then we watched the <a href="http://www.apple.com/apple-events/october-2012/">keynote</a>. Tim Cook took the stage as usual. Boring. Then <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Schiller">Phil Schiller </a>came in. We kinda like this guy. As my wife said, "Phil doesn't try to be Steve Jobs when he's on stage." I agreed with her. He showed the new 13" Macbook Pro with Retina Display, new Mac Mini, and then. <a href="http://www.apple.com/imac/features/">The new iMac</a>. It's amazing. I was stunned. Very thin. Very beautiful. It deserves the title of the queen of the event.</p>

<p>But what excites me the most about this iMac is it feels Job-sy. First, it's unexpected. Nobody predicted this. Everybody was so busy talking about the iPad mini. No rumors (as far as I know) talked about the new iMac. It's the surprise that I have been missing from apple events since the first iPad. Second, Apple made a bold move by removing optical drive from this new iMac. iMac is a desktop computer. With many DVDs and Blu-rays still being sold these days, removing the optical drive from a desktop computer required the guts and courage only Jobs has. And Apple still has it. Good job. Your move, Samsung.</p>

<p><img src="http://mangapournous.m.a.pic.centerblog.net/050930180636_4.gif" alt="Oh, and the Fusion drive in the iMac, sounds so ballsy" /></p>

<p>Final thought, stil hoping for Macbook Air 11" with Retina display…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] TOS. Lie.]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/14/share-tos-lie/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T22:29:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/14/share-tos-lie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://images.cheezburger.com/completestore/2011/8/19/601e324e-1e21-419a-843a-ff22db559ccc.jpg" alt="Biggest lie" /></p>

<p>It's a well known fact that the biggest lie on the internet, or software world, is "I have read the terms of service". Who would have the time (and patience) to read that very long  mambo-jambo? We would use it anyway. Because everybody is using it, right?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are some people who try to fix this culture of lies. There is <a href="http://tos-dr.info/">Terms of Service; Didn't read</a> who tries to simplify the Terms of Service (TOS) of web services and it's doing a pretty good job actually. I just found out that users cannot delete their account in some famous services such as Skype and Wordpress. Surprising.</p>

<p>Another attempt circulating around the tech-sphere recently is <a href="http://rapgenius.com/Apple-itunes-terms-of-service-lyrics">RapGenius' explanations of Apple's iTunes TOS</a> where people are trying to explain some parts of the agreement in witty ways. Though I can't help but wonder what's with the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IX8fKLjC__c">Human Centipede</a> references.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3k3e1j2a1w383o3o0y2g/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-14%20at%209.42.38%20PM.png" alt="iTunes Terms of Service" /></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2T2c0x1p3I1f0W2b0u3J/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-14%20at%209.43.14%20PM.png" alt="It's not so much of agreement" /></p>

<p>If you notice, similar TOS can be found in any other services or softwares. It's not just Apple. Every companies serve us this thing for one simple reason. They don't want us to sue them if anything bad happens.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3g3f0M3E200v2p311f0R/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-14%20at%2010.20.17%20PM.png" alt="500px's TOS" /></p>

<p>The only service that does TOS right is <a href="http://500px.com/">500px</a>. Every companies should follow <a href="http://500px.com/terms">500px's way of presenting TOS</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
