<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Apple | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-22T23:40:30+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[#ExplainAppleKeynoteBadly]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/09/10/number-explainapplekeynotebadly/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T11:03:53+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/09/10/number-explainapplekeynotebadly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>September 9 2014 Apple Live Event was not my favorite Apple event. I&#8217;ll even say that it was the <em>worst</em> Apple event ever. I haven&#8217;t rewatched the keynote (probably never will) and haven&#8217;t read any reviews of the keynote. So here&#8217;s my review.</p>

<!--more-->


<ol>
<li>Tim Cook decided to hold the event in a different place from where they usually did in the past. This resulted in a terrible streaming quality where I completely missed what&#8217;s so great about the new iPhones.</li>
<li>Apple was trying to explain to developers that they should have <code>Localizable.strings (Chinese)</code> file in their app by hiring a Chinese lady to speak non-stop louder than Phil Schiller.</li>
<li>iPhone 6 is amazing. Freeze. Claps. Mute.  Repeat.</li>
<li>Tim Cook disappointed when nobody recognized the voice of Justin Timberlake.</li>
<li>Something exciting about paying things with iPhone. In US only. Because other countries are secondary. Except China. China got the unstoppable live translation.</li>
<li>PAY requires you to <em>still</em> pay for things you buy. Much innovation.</li>
<li>Jony Ive had pimples problem that they removed him from his white room prison.</li>
<li>Apple brought &#8220;One More Thing&#8221; back from the grave.</li>
<li>Apple revealed a watch because that&#8217;s what the society needs right now.</li>
<li>iTime? iWatch? iPrefix is so last year that Apple chose Unicode Symbol as prefix from now on.</li>
<li>Digital Crown on WATCH (ALL CAPITAL, PLEASE) because calling it <em>Dial</em> sounds so cheap.</li>
<li>An ex-Adobe Bill Gates doppelgänger demoed WATCH where he hardly use the <em>innovative</em> Digital Crown and touch the screen most of the time instead. Tim will be pissed.</li>
<li>Apple invented new way of communication without words via the WATCH. Because F__K words. Pre-historic way of communicating is the trend of the future.</li>
<li>YOUTUBE ON STAGE! Oh, it&#8217;s U2. Misheard thanks to poor quality streaming.</li>
<li>Tim Cook and U2 slapstick was so bad that everyone wished the Chinese lady started talking again.</li>
<li>FREE U2 ALBUM FOR EVERYONE! Not sure if you can delete it from your iTunes library though.</li>
<li>That white structure? Yeah, nothing special about it.</li>
<li>No Craig Federighi.</li>
<li>Still no Macbook Air 11&#8221; Retina Display.</li>
</ol>


<p>I think the Reality Distortion Field has worn off on me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Script to Download Wwdc 2014 Videos]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/06/26/script-to-download-wwdc-2014-videos/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-26T23:38:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/06/26/script-to-download-wwdc-2014-videos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2m2M471z1O072F1F0B2u/Screen%20Shot%202014-06-26%20at%2023.54.57.png" alt="Script to download wwdc 14 videos" /></p>

<p>Although I&#8217;ll be most likely sleeping, I&#8217;m planning to catch up with WWDC 14 videos and watch some on the plane this weekend. I can easily download the videos via WWDC app. However they&#8217;ll eat up my iPhone&#8217;s free space. And I also want to speed up the videos a little bit. But downloading the videos one by one from the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/wwdc/2014/">download page</a> is too barbaric.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There must be a script to download them all in one click. Google top search result returns this <a href="https://github.com/ohoachuck/wwdc-downloader">wwdc-downloader</a>, this <a href="http://samwize.com/2014/06/06/download-all-wwdc-2014-pdf-slides-only/">script to download PDF only or the HD videos</a>, and <a href="http://andrewcook.org/2014/06/07/download-wwdc-2014-videos/">this script to download the SD videos</a>. But for some reasons they didn&#8217;t work.</p>

<p>With a slight modification to those last two scripts, I managed to download the SD videos.</p>

<pre><code class="bash">    curl https://developer.apple.com/videos/wwdc/2014/ | grep -iIoh '|.*http.*._sd_.*dl=1' | sed -e 's/|.*"//g' | sed -e 's/\?dl=1//g'|xargs -n1 curl --remote-name
</code></pre>

<p>Then to speed up the videos by 1.3x, I used ffmpeg.</p>

<pre><code class="bash">    find . -name '*.mov' -exec ffmpeg -i {} -filter_complex "[0:v]setpts=10/13*PTS[v];[0:a]atempo=1.3[a]" -map "[v]" -map "[a]" {}@2x.mov \;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Verse]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/01/19/your-verse/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-19T22:27:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/01/19/your-verse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/jiyIcz7wUH0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p><br/>
<em>You don’t read and write poetry because it’s cute, we read and write poetry because we are members of the human race and the human race is filled with passion, medicine, law, business, engineering, these are noble pursuits necessary to sustain life but poetry beauty, romance, love, these are what we stay alive for. The quote from Whitman:</em></p>

<p><em>Oh me! Oh life! of the questions of these recurring,
Of the endless trains of the faithless, of cities fill’d with the foolish,
- What good amid these, O me, O life?</em></p>

<p><em>Answer. That you are here—that life exists and identity. That the powerful play goes on, and you may contribute a verse. <strong>That the powerful play goes on, and that you can contribute a verse, what will your verse be?</strong></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[iOS] Things I Bet You Don't Know About Promoting Your App]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/11/ios-things-i-bet-you-dont-know-about-promoting-your-app/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T11:04:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/11/ios-things-i-bet-you-dont-know-about-promoting-your-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you didn&#8217;t know, I just released a new version of my old app, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/scribeit/id369606127?mt=8">Scribeit</a>. While I was looking for a way to promote and market it, I figured maybe Apple has some tips and tricks to do this. So I went to iTunes Connect and I noticed there was <a href="https://developer.apple.com/appstore/AppStoreMarketingGuidelines.pdf">App Store Marketing and Advertising Guidelines for Developers</a>. I visit iTunes Connect frequently to check Sales and Trends or Payments and Financial Reports, but never bothered to read it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And to my surprise, there are some rules that I never thought they would exist. Some interesting ones are:</p>

<ol>
<li>Never refer to Apple Operating System. Meaning, you must not ever say &#8220;Now Available on iOS&#8221;. Or &#8220;Scribeit for iOS&#8221;. Instead, refer to Apple product names, such as &#8220;Scribeit for iPhone.&#8221; Oops, need to make some change in <a href="http://scribeit.appsccelerated.com/">Scribeit website</a> ^ ^;</li>
<li>Never typeset Apple product names using all uppercase letters. So IPHONE or IPAD is not allowed, people.</li>
<li>Never use a Myriad font for App Store-related text. ⊙０⊙ Why? Anybody care to explain? What&#8217;s with Myriad font?</li>
</ol>


<p>And many more. You should read it. It&#8217;s pretty <em>interesting</em>.</p>

<p>Note:</p>

<p>Thank you for reading this post. Have you checked out my app, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/scribeit/id369606127?mt=8">Scribeit</a>. I think you&#8217;ll love it (⌒▽⌒)☆</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] RDF: It's in the Juice]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/10/thoughts-rdf-its-in-the-juice/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-10T12:29:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/10/thoughts-rdf-its-in-the-juice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004W2UBYW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=everlasti-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004W2UBYW">Walter Isaacson&#8217;s Steve Jobs</a>, regarding Job&#8217;s superpower Reality Distortion Field:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>There was little that could shield you from the force, Hertzfeld discovered. “Amazingly, the reality distortion field seemed to be effective even if you were acutely aware of it. We would often discuss potential techniques for grounding it, but after a while most of us gave up, accepting it as a force of nature.” After Jobs decreed that the sodas in the office refrigerator be replaced by Odwalla organic orange and carrot juices, someone on the team had T-shirts made. “Reality Distortion Field,” they said on the front, and on the back, “It’s in the juice!”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>I want that T-shirt!!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>The result was that the Macintosh team came to share Jobs’s passion for making a great product, not just a profitable one. “Jobs thought of himself as an artist, and he encouraged the design team to think of ourselves that way too,” said Hertzfeld. “The goal was never to beat the competition, or to make a lot of money. It was to do the greatest thing possible, or even a little greater.” He once took the team to see an exhibit of Tiffany glass at the Metropolitan Museum in Manhattan because he believed they could learn from Louis Tiffany’s example of creating great art that could be mass-produced. Recalled Bud Tribble, “We said to ourselves, ‘Hey, if we’re going to make things in our lives, we might as well make them beautiful.’”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>The end results are indeed amazing. But the process seemed so painful. If I have the chance to lead a team, I&#8217;d rather doing it in a fun way. Life is short anyway, why not having fun?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
