<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apple | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-09T12:03:17+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHT] The World Could Have Gotten iBicycle]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/09/thought-the-world-could-have-gotten-ibicycle/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T11:54:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/09/thought-the-world-could-have-gotten-ibicycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004W2UBYW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=everlasti-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004W2UBYW">Walter Isaacson's Steve Jobs</a>, the Mac was initially called <strong>Annie</strong>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>One of Raskin’s dreams was to build an inexpensive computer for the masses, and in 1979 he convinced Mike Markkula to put him in charge of a small development project code-named “Annie” to do just that. Since Raskin thought it was sexist to name computers after women, he redubbed the project in honor of his favorite type of apple, the McIntosh. But he changed the spelling in order not to conflict with the name of the audio equipment maker McIntosh Laboratory. The proposed computer became known as the Macintosh.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Today I learned that a guy named Jef Raskin was the <em>biological</em> father of what we know now as Mac.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>In various interviews, Jobs had been referring to computers as a bicycle for the mind; the ability of humans to create a bicycle allowed them to move more efficiently than even a condor, and likewise the ability to create computers would multiply the efficiency of their minds. So one day Jobs decreed that henceforth the Macintosh should be known instead as the Bicycle. This did not go over well. “Burrell and I thought this was the silliest thing we ever heard, and we simply refused to use the new name,” recalled Hertzfeld. Within a month the idea was dropped.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>Thank God there were people who dared to stand up to Steve for his silly decisions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] Jobs was a Romantic]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/07/share-jobs-was-a-romantic/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T09:48:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/07/share-jobs-was-a-romantic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2E1m0R0422463g2p3M3n/%E5%86%99%E7%9C%9F%202013-01-07%209%2029%2039.jpg" alt="Xerox and Lisa" /></p>

<p>Chapter 8 of Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson on the <em>myth of Apple stealing from Xerox</em>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Xerox’s venture capital division wanted to be part of the second round of Apple financing during the summer of 1979. Jobs made an offer: “I will let you invest a million dollars in Apple if you will open the kimono at PARC.” Xerox accepted. It agreed to show Apple its new technology and in return got to buy 100,000 shares at about $10 each.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>So much for the stealing. Better call it fair trade.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Continuing,</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>As he once said, “Picasso had a saying—‘good artists copy, great artists steal’—and we have always been shameless about stealing great ideas.”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>Jobs was a romantic. He liked to exaggerate things. However, he was a good executioner:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Jobs and his engineers significantly improved the graphical interface ideas they saw at Xerox PARC, and then were able to implement them in ways that Xerox never could accomplish. For example, the Xerox mouse had three buttons, was complicated, cost $300 apiece, and didn’t roll around smoothly; a few days after his second Xerox PARC visit, Jobs went to a local industrial design firm, IDEO, and told one of its founders, Dean Hovey, that he wanted a simple single-button model that cost $15, “and I want to be able to use it on Formica and my blue jeans.” Hovey complied.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>and ..</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Apple’s engineers devised an interface so you could not only drag windows and files around, you could even drop them into folders.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>He had a good team as well:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>One of Atkinson’s amazing feats (which we are so accustomed to nowadays that we rarely marvel at it) was to allow the windows on a screen to overlap so that the “top” one clipped into the ones “below” it.</p></p><p><p>…</p></p><p><p>Atkinson pushed himself to make this trick work because he thought he had seen this capability during his visit to Xerox PARC. In fact the folks at PARC had never accomplished it, and they later told him they were amazed that he had done so.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>So Jobs and team not only got a piece of technology for a price, but they also improved the hell out of it. Impressive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Be an iOS developer now]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/26/thoughts-be-an-ios-developer-now/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-26T17:43:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/26/thoughts-be-an-ios-developer-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Because it's still a great time as app developer.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/cg6O5.jpg" alt="iPad is winning" /></p>

<p>The picture above (via <a href="https://twitter.com/waxpancake/status/283736105717755904">@waxpancake</a>) speaks two things at least. First, Apple must be selling tons of iPads. Second, iOS users are active and proud of using Apple device. As an iOS developer, these two things are good news.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And this report from <a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2012/12/24/apple-microsoft-sony-store-traffic/">CNNMoney</a> is not a good sign for Microsoft and Sony. People don't wait for Santa to come at their homes anymore. They just go to Apple Store apparently.</p>

<p><img src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apple.jpg" alt="Apple Store" /></p>

<p><img src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo1.jpg" alt="Microsoft store" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] The ugliest view in iOS 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/17/thoughts-the-ugliest-view-in-ios-6/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:32:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/17/thoughts-the-ugliest-view-in-ios-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0K401B2o1L0W1z0U3f1O/%E5%86%99%E7%9C%9F%202012-12-17%200%2030%2009.png" alt="This, so damn ugly" /></p>

<p>The previous design of iOS Phone's keypad was so much better. This new one in iOS 6 feels like something made by Android engineer.  （；¬＿¬)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] iPad Mini after 3 days]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/05/thoughts-ipad-mini-after-3-days/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T22:57:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/05/thoughts-ipad-mini-after-3-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2012/11/05Apple-Sells-Three-Million-iPads-in-Three-Days.html">Apple managed to sell three million iPads in three days</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>CUPERTINO, California—November 5, 2012—Apple® today announced it has sold three million iPads in just three days since the launch of its new iPad® mini and fourth generation iPad—double the previous first weekend milestone of 1.5 million Wi-Fi only models sold for the third generation iPad in March.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I can't believe it's been three days since I started using iPad Mini. It feels like I've been using it for a long time. It just fits to my life (and my jacket pocket and my bag) better than the big bro iPad. Even without the retina display, I enjoy reading books and articles on it. Apparently I am not the only one.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Interesting bits on the announcement is that Apple didn't announce how many iPad Mini they have sold. It's 3 millions iPads which include both iPad Mini and the iPad 4 (or the Newer iPad, whatever). So I thought it could also mean that the majority of the iPads sold is the iPad 4 and nobody wanted iPad mini. But Mr. Tim Cook answered in the next paragraph,</p>

<p><blockquote><p>“Customers around the world love the new iPad mini and fourth generation iPad,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “We set a new launch weekend record and practically sold out of iPad minis. We're working hard to build more quickly to meet the incredible demand.”</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Sold out. So the <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/felix-salmon/2012/10/24/why-apple-doesnt-care-about-its-competition/">pricing indeed was not intended to compete with the competitors' tablet</a>, but to fill up the gap between Apple's line of products.</p>

<p>But why didn't Apple announce the real number of iPad mini sold? Now that I think about it, the answer to this question proves that what I thought about Apple was wrong. I didn't write or post or tweet about that thought (because you know, you don't really have to tell your so-called friends and followers about everything), but I was hoping Apple was not going to make iPad mini. I thought by releasing a small version of the iPad <em>after</em> Google released the most praised Android tablet, Google Nexus 7, Apple has fallen back and became a <em>follower</em>. But it seems not the case here. iPad mini is to iPad what Macbook Air is to Macbook Pro. Or it can also be, iPad mini is to iPad what Macbook Air 11" is to Macbook Air 13". As far as I know, Apple never announced individual numbers of MBA and MBP sold. Or each numbers of MBA 11" and MBA 13". They are all Macbooks. They are the choices Apple gives to the customers. Same with the iPads.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0C2w2H44473i1b313m2A/IMG_7552%20copy.jpg" alt="iPad mini" /></p>

<p>I have a feeling that when Apple finally releases iPad mini with retina display, the history of iPhone cannibalizing the iPod will repeat once again. We'll see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
