<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apple | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-02T18:26:22+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Verse]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/01/19/your-verse/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-19T22:27:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2014/01/19/your-verse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/jiyIcz7wUH0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>




<br/>


<p><em>You don’t read and write poetry because it’s cute, we read and write poetry because we are members of the human race and the human race is filled with passion, medicine, law, business, engineering, these are noble pursuits necessary to sustain life but poetry beauty, romance, love, these are what we stay alive for. The quote from Whitman:</em></p>

<p><em>Oh me! Oh life! of the questions of these recurring,
Of the endless trains of the faithless, of cities fill’d with the foolish,
- What good amid these, O me, O life?</em></p>

<p><em>Answer. That you are here—that life exists and identity. That the powerful play goes on, and you may contribute a verse. <strong>That the powerful play goes on, and that you can contribute a verse, what will your verse be?</strong></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[iOS] Things I Bet You Don't Know About Promoting Your App]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/11/ios-things-i-bet-you-dont-know-about-promoting-your-app/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T11:04:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/11/ios-things-i-bet-you-dont-know-about-promoting-your-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you didn't know, I just released a new version of my old app, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/scribeit/id369606127?mt=8">Scribeit</a>. While I was looking for a way to promote and market it, I figured maybe Apple has some tips and tricks to do this. So I went to iTunes Connect and I noticed there was <a href="https://developer.apple.com/appstore/AppStoreMarketingGuidelines.pdf">App Store Marketing and Advertising Guidelines for Developers</a>. I visit iTunes Connect frequently to check Sales and Trends or Payments and Financial Reports, but never bothered to read it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And to my surprise, there are some rules that I never thought they would exist. Some interesting ones are:</p>

<ol>
<li>Never refer to Apple Operating System. Meaning, you must not ever say "Now Available on iOS". Or "Scribeit for iOS". Instead, refer to Apple product names, such as "Scribeit for iPhone." Oops, need to make some change in <a href="http://scribeit.appsccelerated.com/">Scribeit website</a> ^ ^;</li>
<li>Never typeset Apple product names using all uppercase letters. So IPHONE or IPAD is not allowed, people.</li>
<li>Never use a Myriad font for App Store-related text. ⊙０⊙ Why? Anybody care to explain? What's with Myriad font?</li>
</ol>


<p>And many more. You should read it. It's pretty <em>interesting</em>.</p>

<p>Note:</p>

<p>Thank you for reading this post. Have you checked out my app, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/scribeit/id369606127?mt=8">Scribeit</a>. I think you'll love it (⌒▽⌒)☆</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] RDF: It's in the Juice]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/10/thoughts-rdf-its-in-the-juice/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-10T12:29:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/10/thoughts-rdf-its-in-the-juice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004W2UBYW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=everlasti-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004W2UBYW">Walter Isaacson's Steve Jobs</a>, regarding Job's superpower Reality Distortion Field:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>There was little that could shield you from the force, Hertzfeld discovered. “Amazingly, the reality distortion field seemed to be effective even if you were acutely aware of it. We would often discuss potential techniques for grounding it, but after a while most of us gave up, accepting it as a force of nature.” After Jobs decreed that the sodas in the office refrigerator be replaced by Odwalla organic orange and carrot juices, someone on the team had T-shirts made. “Reality Distortion Field,” they said on the front, and on the back, “It’s in the juice!”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>I want that T-shirt!!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>The result was that the Macintosh team came to share Jobs’s passion for making a great product, not just a profitable one. “Jobs thought of himself as an artist, and he encouraged the design team to think of ourselves that way too,” said Hertzfeld. “The goal was never to beat the competition, or to make a lot of money. It was to do the greatest thing possible, or even a little greater.” He once took the team to see an exhibit of Tiffany glass at the Metropolitan Museum in Manhattan because he believed they could learn from Louis Tiffany’s example of creating great art that could be mass-produced. Recalled Bud Tribble, “We said to ourselves, ‘Hey, if we’re going to make things in our lives, we might as well make them beautiful.’”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>The end results are indeed amazing. But the process seemed so painful. If I have the chance to lead a team, I'd rather doing it in a fun way. Life is short anyway, why not having fun?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHT] The World Could Have Gotten iBicycle]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/09/thought-the-world-could-have-gotten-ibicycle/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T11:54:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/09/thought-the-world-could-have-gotten-ibicycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004W2UBYW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=everlasti-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004W2UBYW">Walter Isaacson's Steve Jobs</a>, the Mac was initially called <strong>Annie</strong>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>One of Raskin’s dreams was to build an inexpensive computer for the masses, and in 1979 he convinced Mike Markkula to put him in charge of a small development project code-named “Annie” to do just that. Since Raskin thought it was sexist to name computers after women, he redubbed the project in honor of his favorite type of apple, the McIntosh. But he changed the spelling in order not to conflict with the name of the audio equipment maker McIntosh Laboratory. The proposed computer became known as the Macintosh.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Today I learned that a guy named Jef Raskin was the <em>biological</em> father of what we know now as Mac.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>In various interviews, Jobs had been referring to computers as a bicycle for the mind; the ability of humans to create a bicycle allowed them to move more efficiently than even a condor, and likewise the ability to create computers would multiply the efficiency of their minds. So one day Jobs decreed that henceforth the Macintosh should be known instead as the Bicycle. This did not go over well. “Burrell and I thought this was the silliest thing we ever heard, and we simply refused to use the new name,” recalled Hertzfeld. Within a month the idea was dropped.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>Thank God there were people who dared to stand up to Steve for his silly decisions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] Jobs was a Romantic]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/07/share-jobs-was-a-romantic/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T09:48:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/07/share-jobs-was-a-romantic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2E1m0R0422463g2p3M3n/%E5%86%99%E7%9C%9F%202013-01-07%209%2029%2039.jpg" alt="Xerox and Lisa" /></p>

<p>Chapter 8 of Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson on the <em>myth of Apple stealing from Xerox</em>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Xerox’s venture capital division wanted to be part of the second round of Apple financing during the summer of 1979. Jobs made an offer: “I will let you invest a million dollars in Apple if you will open the kimono at PARC.” Xerox accepted. It agreed to show Apple its new technology and in return got to buy 100,000 shares at about $10 each.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>So much for the stealing. Better call it fair trade.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Continuing,</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>As he once said, “Picasso had a saying—‘good artists copy, great artists steal’—and we have always been shameless about stealing great ideas.”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>Jobs was a romantic. He liked to exaggerate things. However, he was a good executioner:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Jobs and his engineers significantly improved the graphical interface ideas they saw at Xerox PARC, and then were able to implement them in ways that Xerox never could accomplish. For example, the Xerox mouse had three buttons, was complicated, cost $300 apiece, and didn’t roll around smoothly; a few days after his second Xerox PARC visit, Jobs went to a local industrial design firm, IDEO, and told one of its founders, Dean Hovey, that he wanted a simple single-button model that cost $15, “and I want to be able to use it on Formica and my blue jeans.” Hovey complied.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>and ..</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Apple’s engineers devised an interface so you could not only drag windows and files around, you could even drop them into folders.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>He had a good team as well:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>One of Atkinson’s amazing feats (which we are so accustomed to nowadays that we rarely marvel at it) was to allow the windows on a screen to overlap so that the “top” one clipped into the ones “below” it.</p></p><p><p>…</p></p><p><p>Atkinson pushed himself to make this trick work because he thought he had seen this capability during his visit to Xerox PARC. In fact the folks at PARC had never accomplished it, and they later told him they were amazed that he had done so.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>So Jobs and team not only got a piece of technology for a price, but they also improved the hell out of it. Impressive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
