<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-09T12:03:17+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHT] The World Could Have Gotten iBicycle]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/09/thought-the-world-could-have-gotten-ibicycle/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T11:54:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/09/thought-the-world-could-have-gotten-ibicycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004W2UBYW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=everlasti-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004W2UBYW">Walter Isaacson's Steve Jobs</a>, the Mac was initially called <strong>Annie</strong>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>One of Raskin’s dreams was to build an inexpensive computer for the masses, and in 1979 he convinced Mike Markkula to put him in charge of a small development project code-named “Annie” to do just that. Since Raskin thought it was sexist to name computers after women, he redubbed the project in honor of his favorite type of apple, the McIntosh. But he changed the spelling in order not to conflict with the name of the audio equipment maker McIntosh Laboratory. The proposed computer became known as the Macintosh.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Today I learned that a guy named Jef Raskin was the <em>biological</em> father of what we know now as Mac.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>In various interviews, Jobs had been referring to computers as a bicycle for the mind; the ability of humans to create a bicycle allowed them to move more efficiently than even a condor, and likewise the ability to create computers would multiply the efficiency of their minds. So one day Jobs decreed that henceforth the Macintosh should be known instead as the Bicycle. This did not go over well. “Burrell and I thought this was the silliest thing we ever heard, and we simply refused to use the new name,” recalled Hertzfeld. Within a month the idea was dropped.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>Thank God there were people who dared to stand up to Steve for his silly decisions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] I Hate Money]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/08/thoughts-i-hate-money/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T09:23:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/08/thoughts-i-hate-money</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jobs on <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004W2UBYW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=everlasti-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004W2UBYW">Walter Isaacson's Steve Jobs</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>I never worried about money. I grew up in a middle-class family, so I never thought I would starve. And I learned at Atari that I could be an okay engineer, so I always knew I could get by. I was voluntarily poor when I was in college and India, and I lived a pretty simple life even when I was working. So I went from fairly poor, which was wonderful, because I didn’t have to worry about money, to being incredibly rich, when I also didn’t have to worry about money.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Lucky him. Money depresses me everytime. Actually, thinking about money depresses me. It's not that I lack money. It's enough to enjoy and stay alive. And I'm very grateful for it. It's just not enough to make me not to worry about it. I'm not worrying about it every seconds. But it just has to come from time to time to slap me in the face to remind me to worry about it. Are you following me? Me neither.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] Jobs was a Romantic]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/07/share-jobs-was-a-romantic/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T09:48:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/07/share-jobs-was-a-romantic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2E1m0R0422463g2p3M3n/%E5%86%99%E7%9C%9F%202013-01-07%209%2029%2039.jpg" alt="Xerox and Lisa" /></p>

<p>Chapter 8 of Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson on the <em>myth of Apple stealing from Xerox</em>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Xerox’s venture capital division wanted to be part of the second round of Apple financing during the summer of 1979. Jobs made an offer: “I will let you invest a million dollars in Apple if you will open the kimono at PARC.” Xerox accepted. It agreed to show Apple its new technology and in return got to buy 100,000 shares at about $10 each.</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>So much for the stealing. Better call it fair trade.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Continuing,</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>As he once said, “Picasso had a saying—‘good artists copy, great artists steal’—and we have always been shameless about stealing great ideas.”</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>Jobs was a romantic. He liked to exaggerate things. However, he was a good executioner:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Jobs and his engineers significantly improved the graphical interface ideas they saw at Xerox PARC, and then were able to implement them in ways that Xerox never could accomplish. For example, the Xerox mouse had three buttons, was complicated, cost $300 apiece, and didn’t roll around smoothly; a few days after his second Xerox PARC visit, Jobs went to a local industrial design firm, IDEO, and told one of its founders, Dean Hovey, that he wanted a simple single-button model that cost $15, “and I want to be able to use it on Formica and my blue jeans.” Hovey complied.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>and ..</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Apple’s engineers devised an interface so you could not only drag windows and files around, you could even drop them into folders.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>He had a good team as well:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>One of Atkinson’s amazing feats (which we are so accustomed to nowadays that we rarely marvel at it) was to allow the windows on a screen to overlap so that the “top” one clipped into the ones “below” it.</p></p><p><p>…</p></p><p><p>Atkinson pushed himself to make this trick work because he thought he had seen this capability during his visit to Xerox PARC. In fact the folks at PARC had never accomplished it, and they later told him they were amazed that he had done so.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>So Jobs and team not only got a piece of technology for a price, but they also improved the hell out of it. Impressive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] January 4 was my real new year]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/05/thoughts-january-4-was-my-real-new-year/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T01:06:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/05/thoughts-january-4-was-my-real-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I write this sentence on my MBA which rests on my lap, the digital clock at the top right corner shows "Fri Jan 4 11:26:50 PM". In around 30 minutes, it will be January 5. It's been 4 days since the year 2013 closed the door of 2012 and came to our life. The holiday for most people in Japan has ended yesterday. Yet here I am feeling like finally I can say "Happy new year!" sincerelly.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Danny Choo asked good questions on his post <a href="http://www.dannychoo.com/post/en/26806/2013+New+Years+Greetings.html">2013 New Years Greetings!</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Happy new year folks! Hows your new year celebrations?<br/>But before you answer that, have you ever thought to yourself why we celebrate the new year? Is it because we want to celebrate what we have achieved in the previous year? Is it because we are celebrating what we want to do in the up n coming year? Is it because we are celebrating the fact that most of us get time off work/school?</p></blockquote></p>

<p>In my opinion, new year is a good time to start things new. Either starting something really new, or simply restarting what we have been doing. But remember what <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix_Revolutions">Oracle</a> said,</p>

<p><blockquote><p>everything that has a beginning has an end</p></blockquote></p>

<p>There are ways to read that between the line, but I'd like to think that to really begin, we need to end something. I had not finished what I wanted to finish in 2012. Thus, I did not fully celebrate new year.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0G3e350L3m1a2K1N0U1M/Screen%20Shot%202013-01-04%20at%2011.42.19%20PM.png" alt="Last day of 2011 with friends in Ise" /></p>

<p>This year, we, as in me and wifey, <em>celebrated</em> new year differently compared to previous years. Last year, we spent new year in Ise together with our friends. However, this year it was just the two of us in our apartment. We were just there sitting on the yellow sofa I got nearly three years ago, if my memory serves me right, from an Indian guy whom I didn't (still don't) know. We were watching Japanese TV Show called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K%C5%8Dhaku_Uta_Gassen">Kohaku (紅白) Uta Gassen</a> where a bunch of Japanese singers and musicians was divided into two teams, red and white teams, and they competed with each other.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/222Q0y0W1Y2h3I3s460T/maki-chan1.png" alt="Maki-chan on Kohaku" /></p>

<p>But we weren't really watching the show. We were most of the time looking at our Macbook's monitors. I was busy with XCode while wifey was busy with Photoshop. We were working on Scribeit. Scribeit is the second app I put in Apple Store. It is my first paid app. And it is the only paid app at this moment. It's been two years since I updated it. It was never even updated to support retina display when iPhone 4 was released. Despite of that, number of downloads every month never reaches zero. So I finally made up my mind to update this baby and to finish it before 2012 came to an end. And my wife helped me with the graphics and stuff.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2B081D0J0h1c0c450312/9gag2013.png" alt="2013 is the first year since 1987 to have four different numbers" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, everything doesn't always work as planned. As this part of the world turned from December 31 to January 1, Scribeit was not completely done yet. An unexpected behaviour in the app prevented me from fully enjoying the moment where people celebrated the first year since 1987 to have four different numbers!</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3h0o2n1X3a3T0j0R1y0s/Screen%20Shot%202013-01-05%20at%2012.17.08%20AM.png" alt="New Scribeit 2013" /></p>

<p>At around 3AM of January 1, I finally found the problem. I closed my Mac and decided to wrap things up in the morning. Then came January 2. Followed by January 3. You see, I realized that contrary to popular belief, <em>finishing</em> is way more difficult than starting. You can always start <em>small</em>, but you cannot finish small. You can start from small things one by one. But you cannot finish only a part of the whole. Of course there's no such thing as completely <strong>finish</strong>. There's always something to add. Or to reduce. I'm talking about finishing the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product">MVP</a>. You cannot ship a half ass product. You need to reach that state of MVP. And here's a fact: even an MVP has many check lists to complete. If you think starting is hard, finishing will be hell for you.</p>

<p>So, on the last day of new year holiday, I was finally able to submit our baby to App Store. We think it looks amazing. We love it. And we think you'll love it too. ♡＾▽＾♡ Follow me on <a href="https://twitter.com/nicnocquee">Twitter</a> to know when the update is available on the App Store.</p>

<p>☆☆ Happy new year!</p>

<p>☆☆ 明けましておめでとうございます！</p>

<p>☆☆ Selamat tahun baru!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Be an iOS developer now]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/26/thoughts-be-an-ios-developer-now/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-26T17:43:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/26/thoughts-be-an-ios-developer-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Because it's still a great time as app developer.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/cg6O5.jpg" alt="iPad is winning" /></p>

<p>The picture above (via <a href="https://twitter.com/waxpancake/status/283736105717755904">@waxpancake</a>) speaks two things at least. First, Apple must be selling tons of iPads. Second, iOS users are active and proud of using Apple device. As an iOS developer, these two things are good news.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And this report from <a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2012/12/24/apple-microsoft-sony-store-traffic/">CNNMoney</a> is not a good sign for Microsoft and Sony. People don't wait for Santa to come at their homes anymore. They just go to Apple Store apparently.</p>

<p><img src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apple.jpg" alt="Apple Store" /></p>

<p><img src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo1.jpg" alt="Microsoft store" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
