<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-30T00:05:20+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] I hope Apple will never do this]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-i-hope-apple-will-never-do-this/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T23:39:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-i-hope-apple-will-never-do-this</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By "this" I mean what <a href="http://www.amazon.com/">Amazon</a> just did:</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2b351X3f1J0y2K1q0x23/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-29%20at%2010.48.51%20PM.png" alt="Amazon attack iPad mini" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>or what Samsung did:</p>

<p><img src="http://kensegall.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/120916_samsung_ad.jpg" alt="Samsung gave a blow at Apple" /></p>

<p>If you still cannot grasp what I mean, it's the crappy way of advertising the product by comparing with the competitor. At least do it in a funny and classy way like Mac vs PC.</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/K0Mt6dqFv4k" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Oh, and if you're interested in the revised versions of the two ads above via <a href="http://m.imore.com/copy-editing-amazons-kindle-fire-vs-ipad-mini-ad">iMore</a></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1U0B083v42051S1N2P2A/amazon_kindle_fire_vs_ipad_mini_v2-2.jpg" alt="Kindle Fire HD vs iPad Mini revised comparison" /></p>

<p>and <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17852_3-57513782-71/apple-fanboys-fight-back-against-samsung/">CNet</a>:</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/25060I3T1V2I440n3Z1C/Real_Samsung_Ad_610x1179.png" alt="Galaxy S3 vs iPhone from Apple fan's point of view" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Lover? Hater? It's all about Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-lover-hater-its-all-about-apple/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T22:31:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/29/thoughts-lover-hater-its-all-about-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Check out these two videos, Shit Android Users Say and Shit Apple Fanatics Say:</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7huae767Rxg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>




<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FFhjDX-DUew" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>




<!-- more -->


<p>It's hard not to notice from the two videos that Android users tend to show their <em>hatred/dislike</em> towards Apple, while on the other hand, Apple users tend to show their <em>love</em> towards Apple itself. Which is kind of weird since we all know that there was one person in Apple who hated Android so much.</p>

<p>I always see those who hate Apple as broken hearted people. It could be an unrequited love. Or it could be a relationship that went wrong at some point. Either way, they cannot help but bitching about Apple for being disappointed.</p>

<p>Android world needs more people who are proud of having an Android device than those who keep complaining about device that they are not going to use anyway.</p>

<p>Anyhow, We just looooooooooooooove Apple. ♡＾▽＾♡ Except the Apple Map. (¬д¬。)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] iMac was the queen of the apple event]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/thoughts-imac-was-the-queen-of-the-apple-event/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T08:11:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/thoughts-imac-was-the-queen-of-the-apple-event</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1v1O2A290s0k0p0r2A1t/ipadmini.jpg" alt="The iPad mini" /></p>

<p>First thing I did this morning when I woke up was to pick up my iPad which was lying on the side of my bed all night, opened Safari, typed in apple.com. iPad mini was the first thing I saw. Watching the video of the iPad mini, me and wifey thought, "we want it!" It looks lighter, and easier to hold.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>But then, John Gruber <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2012/10/23/ipad-mini-dalrymple">said</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Screen resolution-wise, it’s exactly what I expected for a 163 PPI display in 2012: noticeably nicer than the 133 PPI iPad 1/2, noticeably worse than the 266 PPI iPad 3/4. The iPad Mini display seems brighter and to have better contrast than the iPhone 3GS display, but unsurprisingly, rendered text looks exactly like it does on the 3GS.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><strong>Rendered text looks exactly like it does on the 3GS</strong>. Now that's a turn off. The thing I like the most from iPhone 4/4S and the (not so) new iPad was the retina display which display text sharply. If this iPad mini cannot do that, I guess we'll wait for the next generation.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0W142R2S1J3B080O1A0b/imac.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Then we watched the <a href="http://www.apple.com/apple-events/october-2012/">keynote</a>. Tim Cook took the stage as usual. Boring. Then <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Schiller">Phil Schiller </a>came in. We kinda like this guy. As my wife said, "Phil doesn't try to be Steve Jobs when he's on stage." I agreed with her. He showed the new 13" Macbook Pro with Retina Display, new Mac Mini, and then. <a href="http://www.apple.com/imac/features/">The new iMac</a>. It's amazing. I was stunned. Very thin. Very beautiful. It deserves the title of the queen of the event.</p>

<p>But what excites me the most about this iMac is it feels Job-sy. First, it's unexpected. Nobody predicted this. Everybody was so busy talking about the iPad mini. No rumors (as far as I know) talked about the new iMac. It's the surprise that I have been missing from apple events since the first iPad. Second, Apple made a bold move by removing optical drive from this new iMac. iMac is a desktop computer. With many DVDs and Blu-rays still being sold these days, removing the optical drive from a desktop computer required the guts and courage only Jobs has. And Apple still has it. Good job. Your move, Samsung.</p>

<p><img src="http://mangapournous.m.a.pic.centerblog.net/050930180636_4.gif" alt="Oh, and the Fusion drive in the iMac, sounds so ballsy" /></p>

<p>Final thought, stil hoping for Macbook Air 11" with Retina display…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] No reason for Samsung to stop copying Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/23/thoughts-no-reason-for-samsung-to-stop-copying-apple/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T20:33:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/23/thoughts-no-reason-for-samsung-to-stop-copying-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung did it again:</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/A502hRpCQAEZn70.jpg" alt="Macbook Air's doppelganger" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Some previous amusing works by Samsung's designers:</p>

<p><img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m56wdu12es1r3kdlto1_500.jpg" alt="Mac Mini's doppleganger" /></p>

<p><img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ls5kr6QLno1r3kdlto1_500.png" alt="Personally I think this was the best" /></p>

<p>More <a href="http://samsungcopiesapple.tumblr.com/">here</a>.</p>

<p>We all can call Samsung shameless copycat. But there's just no reason, but conscience, to stop executing this strategy. The worst that could happen to them was a mere <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2012/08/jury-returns-verdict-in-apple-v-samsung/">$1 billion</a>. Nothing compared to their <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2012/10/05/samsung-record-7-1-billion-profit/">$7.3 billion profit</a>.</p>

<p>This strategy just works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] Opened Facebook and Twitter after a week]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/27/thoughts-opened-facebook-and-twitter-after-a-week/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T09:49:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/09/27/thoughts-opened-facebook-and-twitter-after-a-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I decided to take a break from Facebook and Twitter. I deleted Facebook and Twitter app from my iPhone and resisted from opening Facebook and Twitter from the web. The reason was pretty simple. I felt that Facebook and Twitter <em>toxicated</em> my mind. There were too many posts or Tweets that were boring, stupid, unnecessary, and I found insulting to what I believe in. To respond to those posts or tweets would not only waste my time, but also mentally exhausting. Not to mention debating over something that will never have common agreement always leaves bad taste in my mouth. Therefore, I chose to keep a distance from Twitter and Facebook.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Surprisingly, I survived without opening them for a week. It was kinda weird feeling. A day without notifications felt like something was missing. There were these empty time slots in my day that I chose to fill with reading one of the books that I have piled up digitally, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SEGEKI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B000SEGEKI&linkCode=as2&tag=everlasti-20">The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=everlasti-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B000SEGEKI" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0O3S1u211Q2D043o070s/Screen%20Shot%202012-09-26%20at%2011.37.54%20AM.png" alt="49 Facebook Notifications" /></p>

<p>Then yesterday I opened Facebook and Twitter. I found two interesting things. The first one was on Facebook. In a week, I got 49 notifications in which only around 10 were comments or likes to my posts from this blog or pics from my Instagram. The rest was new updates from my <em>Closed Friends</em>. Then I scrolled fast through my news feed to see anything interesting. Aside from <a href="http://dallarosa.tumblr.com/">my good friend</a>'s new hair style, nothing was really interesting. So basically, I didn't really miss anything significant. That is interesting.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2y1h0Y1q1d3w3E3s2F1D/Screen%20Shot%202012-09-27%20at%209.47.56%20AM.png" alt="Twitter navigation tab" /></p>

<p>The second interesting thing was in Twitter. Specifically, in Twitter's web page. The first thing I wanted to do on Twitter was to see if any body <em>mentioned</em> me. Unlike Facebook, Twitter doesn't have the red notification bubble. But there was this blue light under the gear icon. So I figured that must be my notifications. But when I clicked it, there was only my Direct Messages. Ok, I still thought, so my Mention notification is not here. I figured maybe it's on the <em>Me</em> icon. I mean, it says Me, so that means everything that belongs to Me should be there, doesn't it? So I clicked it. To my surprise, it wasn't there as well. Where is my "Mentions"?! It can't be in that @Connect, can it? I thought @Connect is the place if you want to find some people to follow, to connect with other users, hence the name @Connect. But I was wrong. My mentions were there. That's interesting. Either me or Twitter don't understand user experience. Anyway, no important mentions after a week. I didn't look at my Twitter streams, cause I knew there must be tons of tweets.</p>

<p>I can say that I am a social network addict. But like everything else, having something excessively is never a good thing. From this one week experiment, I can conclude that once a week Twitter/Facebook consumption is good for my health. So if you have anything important to tell me, please don't do it via Facebook or Twitter. Just email me, or iMessage or text me. Thank you.</p>

<p>Note: Unfortunately, I cannot get away from Instagram. I just couldn't miss seeing Giee-tan for a day! I mean, look at her, she's the cutest cat in the world! ヽ(=^ ･ω･^ =)丿 Follow <a href="instagram://user?username=tiaichima">tiaichima</a> for more pics of Giee! (You have to open that link from your iPhone and must have instagram app installed).</p>

<p><img src="http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/f28ea3f202e811e29e0522000a1e8894_7.jpg" alt="Giee Giee - Cutest cat in the world" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
