<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ios | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-03T12:32:27+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[iOS] Open Source Projects Used in Facebook iOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/05/10/ios-open-source-projects-used-in-facebook-ios/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T20:58:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/05/10/ios-open-source-projects-used-in-facebook-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2O163t1B1i46112q0n1L/Photo%202013-05-10%2021%2003%2015.png" alt="Facebook-Open-Source-Licenses" /></p>

<p>One of my hobby is to star or clone open source iOS components/libraries in Github. There are just many good open source projects there that can speed up app development. And I'm pretty sure many apps in the app store are using these open source libraries. Unfortunately, most apps don't act like good open source citizens by not showing the attributions.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Some big name apps show the attributions in the app. Facebook for example. You can find it in Settings -> Facebook -> Settings -> About. There are many libraries they listed there. But some libraries seem to be server-side libraries. The iOS-related open source libraries (as for version 183159) are</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://code.google.com/p/google-toolbox-for-mac/">Google Toolbox for Mac</a>. I've never used this. Anything insteresting there?</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/robbiehanson/CocoaLumberjack">CocoaLumberjack</a>. Never used this one either. But looking at the README, I think I'll use this from now on.</li>
<li><a href="http://gabriel.github.io/gh-kit/">GHKit</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://goodliffe.blogspot.jp/2010/09/building-boost-framework-for-ios-iphone.html?m=1">Boost for iPhone</a>. Wonder what part they use Boost for.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/AlanQuatermain/AQGridView">AQGridView</a>. For the feeds stream I guess.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jasarien/CoreTextHyperlinkView">CoreTextHyperlinkView</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mikeash/MAZeroingWeakRef">MAZeroingWeakRef</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mikeash/MAZeroingWeakRef">Mixpanel iPhone</a>. So they use Mixpanel for analytics. I wonder if they will acquire it some time in the future.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/msgpack/msgpack-objectivec">MessagePack Objective-C</a>. Just found out about this JSON alternative.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jverkoey/nimbus">Nimbus</a>. Even Facebook is not using Three20 anymore.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jverkoey/ObjQREncoder">Objective-c QR Encoder</a>. Why does the app need this?</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ocrickard/OCPDFGen">OCPDFGen</a>. What feature in the app that requires this library?</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ylechelle/OpenUDID">OpenUDID</a>. Didn't know there is such thing.</li>
<li><a href="https://code.google.com/p/plcrashreporter/">PLCrashReporter</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mikeho/QSUtilities/">QSUtilities</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rs/SDURLCache">SDURLCache</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/RestKit/RestKit">RestKit</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rs/SDWebImage">SDWebImage</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jverkoey/sockit">SOCKit</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sorced-jim/SPDY-for-iPhone">SPDY for iPhone</a>. I don't know what this is for.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tweetdeck/TDOAuth">TDOauth</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/coneybeare/UAModalPanel">UIModalPanel</a>. I don't think they're still using this on the app.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marcuswestin/WebViewJavascriptBridge">WebViewJavascriptBridge</a>. This too.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/amarcadet/XMLReader">XMLReader</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://code.google.com/p/zxing/">ZXing</a>. Barcode again?</li>
</ol>


<p>That's about it. Maybe I missed something though because Facebook makes it really unconvenient to read these attributions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[iOS] Things I Bet You Don't Know About Promoting Your App]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/11/ios-things-i-bet-you-dont-know-about-promoting-your-app/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T11:04:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/11/ios-things-i-bet-you-dont-know-about-promoting-your-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you didn't know, I just released a new version of my old app, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/scribeit/id369606127?mt=8">Scribeit</a>. While I was looking for a way to promote and market it, I figured maybe Apple has some tips and tricks to do this. So I went to iTunes Connect and I noticed there was <a href="https://developer.apple.com/appstore/AppStoreMarketingGuidelines.pdf">App Store Marketing and Advertising Guidelines for Developers</a>. I visit iTunes Connect frequently to check Sales and Trends or Payments and Financial Reports, but never bothered to read it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And to my surprise, there are some rules that I never thought they would exist. Some interesting ones are:</p>

<ol>
<li>Never refer to Apple Operating System. Meaning, you must not ever say "Now Available on iOS". Or "Scribeit for iOS". Instead, refer to Apple product names, such as "Scribeit for iPhone." Oops, need to make some change in <a href="http://scribeit.appsccelerated.com/">Scribeit website</a> ^ ^;</li>
<li>Never typeset Apple product names using all uppercase letters. So IPHONE or IPAD is not allowed, people.</li>
<li>Never use a Myriad font for App Store-related text. ⊙０⊙ Why? Anybody care to explain? What's with Myriad font?</li>
</ol>


<p>And many more. You should read it. It's pretty <em>interesting</em>.</p>

<p>Note:</p>

<p>Thank you for reading this post. Have you checked out my app, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/scribeit/id369606127?mt=8">Scribeit</a>. I think you'll love it (⌒▽⌒)☆</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] January 4 was my real new year]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/05/thoughts-january-4-was-my-real-new-year/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T01:06:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2013/01/05/thoughts-january-4-was-my-real-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I write this sentence on my MBA which rests on my lap, the digital clock at the top right corner shows "Fri Jan 4 11:26:50 PM". In around 30 minutes, it will be January 5. It's been 4 days since the year 2013 closed the door of 2012 and came to our life. The holiday for most people in Japan has ended yesterday. Yet here I am feeling like finally I can say "Happy new year!" sincerelly.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Danny Choo asked good questions on his post <a href="http://www.dannychoo.com/post/en/26806/2013+New+Years+Greetings.html">2013 New Years Greetings!</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Happy new year folks! Hows your new year celebrations?<br/>But before you answer that, have you ever thought to yourself why we celebrate the new year? Is it because we want to celebrate what we have achieved in the previous year? Is it because we are celebrating what we want to do in the up n coming year? Is it because we are celebrating the fact that most of us get time off work/school?</p></blockquote></p>

<p>In my opinion, new year is a good time to start things new. Either starting something really new, or simply restarting what we have been doing. But remember what <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix_Revolutions">Oracle</a> said,</p>

<p><blockquote><p>everything that has a beginning has an end</p></blockquote></p>

<p>There are ways to read that between the line, but I'd like to think that to really begin, we need to end something. I had not finished what I wanted to finish in 2012. Thus, I did not fully celebrate new year.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0G3e350L3m1a2K1N0U1M/Screen%20Shot%202013-01-04%20at%2011.42.19%20PM.png" alt="Last day of 2011 with friends in Ise" /></p>

<p>This year, we, as in me and wifey, <em>celebrated</em> new year differently compared to previous years. Last year, we spent new year in Ise together with our friends. However, this year it was just the two of us in our apartment. We were just there sitting on the yellow sofa I got nearly three years ago, if my memory serves me right, from an Indian guy whom I didn't (still don't) know. We were watching Japanese TV Show called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K%C5%8Dhaku_Uta_Gassen">Kohaku (紅白) Uta Gassen</a> where a bunch of Japanese singers and musicians was divided into two teams, red and white teams, and they competed with each other.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/222Q0y0W1Y2h3I3s460T/maki-chan1.png" alt="Maki-chan on Kohaku" /></p>

<p>But we weren't really watching the show. We were most of the time looking at our Macbook's monitors. I was busy with XCode while wifey was busy with Photoshop. We were working on Scribeit. Scribeit is the second app I put in Apple Store. It is my first paid app. And it is the only paid app at this moment. It's been two years since I updated it. It was never even updated to support retina display when iPhone 4 was released. Despite of that, number of downloads every month never reaches zero. So I finally made up my mind to update this baby and to finish it before 2012 came to an end. And my wife helped me with the graphics and stuff.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2B081D0J0h1c0c450312/9gag2013.png" alt="2013 is the first year since 1987 to have four different numbers" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, everything doesn't always work as planned. As this part of the world turned from December 31 to January 1, Scribeit was not completely done yet. An unexpected behaviour in the app prevented me from fully enjoying the moment where people celebrated the first year since 1987 to have four different numbers!</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3h0o2n1X3a3T0j0R1y0s/Screen%20Shot%202013-01-05%20at%2012.17.08%20AM.png" alt="New Scribeit 2013" /></p>

<p>At around 3AM of January 1, I finally found the problem. I closed my Mac and decided to wrap things up in the morning. Then came January 2. Followed by January 3. You see, I realized that contrary to popular belief, <em>finishing</em> is way more difficult than starting. You can always start <em>small</em>, but you cannot finish small. You can start from small things one by one. But you cannot finish only a part of the whole. Of course there's no such thing as completely <strong>finish</strong>. There's always something to add. Or to reduce. I'm talking about finishing the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product">MVP</a>. You cannot ship a half ass product. You need to reach that state of MVP. And here's a fact: even an MVP has many check lists to complete. If you think starting is hard, finishing will be hell for you.</p>

<p>So, on the last day of new year holiday, I was finally able to submit our baby to App Store. We think it looks amazing. We love it. And we think you'll love it too. ♡＾▽＾♡ Follow me on <a href="https://twitter.com/nicnocquee">Twitter</a> to know when the update is available on the App Store.</p>

<p>☆☆ Happy new year!</p>

<p>☆☆ 明けましておめでとうございます！</p>

<p>☆☆ Selamat tahun baru!</p>

<p>☆☆ <strong>UPDATE!</strong></p>

<p><strong>Scribeit is up in the <a href="http://scribeit.appsccelerated.com/">App Store</a> now! Check it out!
</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] The ugliest view in iOS 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/17/thoughts-the-ugliest-view-in-ios-6/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:32:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/12/17/thoughts-the-ugliest-view-in-ios-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0K401B2o1L0W1z0U3f1O/%E5%86%99%E7%9C%9F%202012-12-17%200%2030%2009.png" alt="This, so damn ugly" /></p>

<p>The previous design of iOS Phone's keypad was so much better. This new one in iOS 6 feels like something made by Android engineer.  （；¬＿¬)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[iOS] Split screen in XCode 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/19/ios-split-screen-in-xcode-4/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T21:48:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/11/19/ios-split-screen-in-xcode-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://cocoaheads.tumblr.com/post/35711948405/xcode-in-a-nutshell"><img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_mdhn7nq1pE1qbs1hto1_1280.png" alt="XCode in a nutshell" /></a></p>

<p>In XCode 4, to have the split screen feature, you have to use the Assistant Editor. It's that ""Black Tie" Mode.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0R0j3V441K2q3H2r0E2c/xcode-split-0.png" alt="Tap the Assistant Editor to split the screen" /></p>

<p>If you don't fancy having the editors horizontally, you can easily stack them vertically by clicking View -> Assistant Editor -> All editors stacked vertically.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0I3P2A2r0o0x1D2G4720/xcode-split-3.png" alt="Change assistant editor layout" /></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0y2k3E213J3Z2T2E2Y0n/xcode-split-4.png" alt="Editors. Stack them all." /></p>

<p>Normally, the assistant editor will automatically show the counterpart of the file opened in the main editor. But if you want to defy the intelligence of the xcode, you can click on the Black Tie icon Counterparts then choose Manual.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/310T0L2n2M3d1h151n2i/xcode-split-5.png" alt="Manually select file to open in assistant editor" /></p>

<p>If you have tons of source codes, it might be difficult to search the file you want to open. Here's the trick. Click on the file name on Assistant Editor bar, then just type the name of the file you're looking for. XCode auto-completion will do the work for you.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1H0J0a3S0q2o1d3K3U0y/xcode-split-67.png" alt="Type file name to open file fast" /></p>

<p>And last, if you're not satisfied with monogamy, you can conduct polygamy up to 5 assistants. You might be able to have more assistants in a bigger screen. But in my Macbook Air, 5 is the limit. Makes sense, cause it's getting too crowded.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2E1X0s2c0w0C2r1r3h3U/xcode-split-8.png" alt="The more the merrier" /></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1t2t0o1f1W1z3g0n1Y15/Screen%20Shot%202012-11-19%20at%2010.06.31%20PM.png" alt="Polygamy in XCode" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
