<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: share | Something Awesome]]></title>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/categories/share/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-25T23:14:37+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://nicnocquee.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nico Prananta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[THOUGHTS] iMac was the queen of the apple event]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/thoughts-imac-was-the-queen-of-the-apple-event/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T08:11:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/24/thoughts-imac-was-the-queen-of-the-apple-event</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1v1O2A290s0k0p0r2A1t/ipadmini.jpg" alt="The iPad mini" /></p>

<p>First thing I did this morning when I woke up was to pick up my iPad which was lying on the side of my bed all night, opened Safari, typed in apple.com. iPad mini was the first thing I saw. Watching the video of the iPad mini, me and wifey thought, "we want it!" It looks lighter, and easier to hold.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>But then, John Gruber <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2012/10/23/ipad-mini-dalrymple">said</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Screen resolution-wise, it’s exactly what I expected for a 163 PPI display in 2012: noticeably nicer than the 133 PPI iPad 1/2, noticeably worse than the 266 PPI iPad 3/4. The iPad Mini display seems brighter and to have better contrast than the iPhone 3GS display, but unsurprisingly, rendered text looks exactly like it does on the 3GS.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><strong>Rendered text looks exactly like it does on the 3GS</strong>. Now that's a turn off. The thing I like the most from iPhone 4/4S and the (not so) new iPad was the retina display which display text sharply. If this iPad mini cannot do that, I guess we'll wait for the next generation.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/0W142R2S1J3B080O1A0b/imac.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Then we watched the <a href="http://www.apple.com/apple-events/october-2012/">keynote</a>. Tim Cook took the stage as usual. Boring. Then <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Schiller">Phil Schiller </a>came in. We kinda like this guy. As my wife said, "Phil doesn't try to be Steve Jobs when he's on stage." I agreed with her. He showed the new 13" Macbook Pro with Retina Display, new Mac Mini, and then. <a href="http://www.apple.com/imac/features/">The new iMac</a>. It's amazing. I was stunned. Very thin. Very beautiful. It deserves the title of the queen of the event.</p>

<p>But what excites me the most about this iMac is it feels Job-sy. First, it's unexpected. Nobody predicted this. Everybody was so busy talking about the iPad mini. No rumors (as far as I know) talked about the new iMac. It's the surprise that I have been missing from apple events since the first iPad. Second, Apple made a bold move by removing optical drive from this new iMac. iMac is a desktop computer. With many DVDs and Blu-rays still being sold these days, removing the optical drive from a desktop computer required the guts and courage only Jobs has. And Apple still has it. Good job. Your move, Samsung.</p>

<p><img src="http://mangapournous.m.a.pic.centerblog.net/050930180636_4.gif" alt="Oh, and the Fusion drive in the iMac, sounds so ballsy" /></p>

<p>Final thought, stil hoping for Macbook Air 11" with Retina display…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] Don't Buy a Kindle]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/23/share-dont-buy-a-kindle/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T02:01:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/23/share-dont-buy-a-kindle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bekkelund.net/">Martin Bekkelund</a> on <a href="http://www.bekkelund.net/2012/10/22/outlawed-by-amazon-drm/">Outlawed by Amazon DRM</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Did she violate any terms? Amazon will not tell. Perhaps by accident? Amazon does not care. The conclusion so far is clear: Amazon closed her account, wiped her Kindle and refuses to tell her why. End of discussion.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>If the claim to be trusted, the fact that Amazon refused to give any reasons is very disturbing. I understand, though not favoring, that Amazon, like Apple, has the right to do pretty much anything they want with their device and platform. But punishing a customer without warning and explanation is far from being classy.</p>

<p>As a husband of a wife who uses Amazon Kindle everyday, I found this news very saddening. Because we like Kindle. The first generation Kindle we have is the best device for reading. Better than the iPad in that area. Not to mention iBook in Japan is pretty much deserted. With its simplicity in purchasing and the vast collection of books, Amazon Kindle has become our favorite book store.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Cory Doctorow on <a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/10/22/kindle-user-claims-amazon-dele.html">Kindle user claims Amazon deleted whole library without explanation</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>This fine print will always have a clause that says you are a mere tenant farmer of your books, and not their owner, and your right to carry around your "purchases" (which are really conditional licenses, despite misleading buttons labelled with words like "Buy this with one click" -- I suppose "Conditionally license this with one click" is deemed too cumbersome for a button) can be revoked without notice or explanation (or, notably, refund) at any time.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I agree with replacing the "Buy this with one click" button to "Conditionally license this with one click". At least people will know that they won't really own what they are about to purchase and proceed with their own risks.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/1X0p312P0E2d2g3q0U3S/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-23%20at%202.01.56%20AM.png" alt="Don't buy a Kindle https://twitter.com/paulg/status/260400550422646785" /></p>

<p>I guess it's inevitable for a company who started small then turned big to become evil. Apple, Google, Twitter, just to name a few. And now (or has it been for a long time?) is Amazon's turn.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>You either die a hero or you live long enough to see yourself become the villain.</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] Quote of the day #1]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/15/share-quote-of-the-day-number-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T21:36:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/15/share-quote-of-the-day-number-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thedoghousediaries.com/4624">Repeating History</a> by Doghouse Diaries:</p>

<p><img src="http://thedoghousediaries.com/comics/uncategorized/2012-10-15-30f166b.png" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>If you wish to make an apple pie from scratch, you must first invent the universe. - Carl Sagan</p></blockquote></p>

<p><a href="http://www.everythingisaremix.info/">Everything is a REMIX</a> indeed. <a href="http://thedoghousediaries.com/">Doghouse Diaries</a> is a pretty funny webcomic. You should follow it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[SHARE] TOS. Lie.]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/14/share-tos-lie/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T22:29:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/14/share-tos-lie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://images.cheezburger.com/completestore/2011/8/19/601e324e-1e21-419a-843a-ff22db559ccc.jpg" alt="Biggest lie" /></p>

<p>It's a well known fact that the biggest lie on the internet, or software world, is "I have read the terms of service". Who would have the time (and patience) to read that very long  mambo-jambo? We would use it anyway. Because everybody is using it, right?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are some people who try to fix this culture of lies. There is <a href="http://tos-dr.info/">Terms of Service; Didn't read</a> who tries to simplify the Terms of Service (TOS) of web services and it's doing a pretty good job actually. I just found out that users cannot delete their account in some famous services such as Skype and Wordpress. Surprising.</p>

<p>Another attempt circulating around the tech-sphere recently is <a href="http://rapgenius.com/Apple-itunes-terms-of-service-lyrics">RapGenius' explanations of Apple's iTunes TOS</a> where people are trying to explain some parts of the agreement in witty ways. Though I can't help but wonder what's with the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IX8fKLjC__c">Human Centipede</a> references.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3k3e1j2a1w383o3o0y2g/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-14%20at%209.42.38%20PM.png" alt="iTunes Terms of Service" /></p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2T2c0x1p3I1f0W2b0u3J/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-14%20at%209.43.14%20PM.png" alt="It's not so much of agreement" /></p>

<p>If you notice, similar TOS can be found in any other services or softwares. It's not just Apple. Every companies serve us this thing for one simple reason. They don't want us to sue them if anything bad happens.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3g3f0M3E200v2p311f0R/Screen%20Shot%202012-10-14%20at%2010.20.17%20PM.png" alt="500px's TOS" /></p>

<p>The only service that does TOS right is <a href="http://500px.com/">500px</a>. Every companies should follow <a href="http://500px.com/terms">500px's way of presenting TOS</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[iPad] Upgraded to iOS 6 for The Magazine]]></title>
    <link href="http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/12/ipad-upgraded-to-ios-6-for-the-magazine/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-12T17:29:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://nicnocquee.com/blog/2012/10/12/ipad-upgraded-to-ios-6-for-the-magazine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.marco.org/">Marco Ament</a> on the <a href="http://the-magazine.org/1/foreword">Foreword of The Magazine</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Many iPad magazines are carrying unnecessary and expensive baggage from their print days. Some born-digital magazines even took on print baggage simply because they thought they needed it.</p></blockquote></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Indeed.</p>

<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/3D3n1h3g0D1Q1s2a0p02/2012-10-12%20at%2005:27.png" alt="The Magazine for iPad" /></p>

<p>With many problems like the <a href="http://9to5mac.com/2012/04/04/apple-investigating-new-ipad-wifi-issues-tells-applecare-to-replace-affected-units/">wifi issue</a>, I have been hesitant to upgrade my iPad to iOS 6. But The Magazine is approved by <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2012/10/11/the-magazine">John Grubber</a>. And concurred by <a href="http://parislemon.com/post/33417889715/marco-arment-launches-the-magazine">MG Siegler</a>. A week free trial. Furthermore, I like reading articles. And this one looks slick. But it needs iOS 6. There, I installed it. Let's see if it's worth it. You can download The Magazine from the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/magazine-for-geeks-like-us./id557744510?mt=8">App Store</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
